<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
  <channel>
    <title>EdSurge Articles</title>
    <link>https://www.edsurge.com/</link>
    <description>EdSurge is an independent information resource and community for everyone involved in education technology</description>
    <copyright>Copyright 2011-2019, EdSurge Inc.</copyright>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://www.edsurge.com/articles_rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 20:55:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 13:03:09 -0600</pubDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.edsurge.com/assets/EdSurgeBoltIconSquare-ef80606f80fc8dae4e5befd16a00dfca47942d96220296a84c276ea2907e2a0b.png</url>
      <title>EdSurge Articles</title>
      <link>https://www.edsurge.com/</link>
    </image>
    <item>
      <title>Innovative Schools Find Lessons — and Opportunities — in Remote Learning</title>
      <link>https://www.edsurge.com/news/2020-04-06-innovative-schools-find-lessons-and-opportunities-in-remote-learning</link>
      <comments>https://www.edsurge.com/news/2020-04-06-innovative-schools-find-lessons-and-opportunities-in-remote-learning#comments</comments>
      <dc:creator>Gaia Ines Fasso</dc:creator>
      <category>Education</category>
      <category>Technology</category>
      <category>Coronavirus</category>
      <category>PK-12 School Models</category>
      <category>Remote Instruction</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 13:03:09 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">
post-guid-b33ead06      </guid>
      <description>Two weeks ago I was due to visit a handful of innovative schools in New York City and the Bay area as part of my research. I am an edtech consultant ...</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Two weeks ago I was due to visit a handful of innovative schools in New York City and the Bay area as part of my research. I am an edtech consultant and student of experience design at the University of the Arts, London. Needless to say, the trips didn’t take place. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Instead, I asked to video conference with my interviewees, which gave me the chance to understand how schools’ closure is shaping learning for the long term. Here’s some of the biggest challenges schools are facing and how they’re making it work despite the uncertainty. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="pullquote"&gt;This is an existential crisis. We have to take care of the staff if we want to take care of our students&lt;/blockquote&gt;John Bosselman&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The rhythm and rituals of learning depend on people, not tech.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;New York’s Academy of Thought and Industry (ATI) is part of a network of Montessori-inspired middle schools, inheriting fifteen former students of AltSchool and its proprietary learning management system. ATI teachers are used to sending and receiving assignments digitally and because of that, the transition to online learning has been smooth so far, principal David Hyman tells me, as he awaits a call from a mentee on day two of closing. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;ATI’s promise to students is to help them develop a sense of agency, independent work and grit: “Stuff that you know only when you see it,” Hyman says. How do you do that in absence of in-person interaction? One-on-one coaching will continue over the phone, he explains, as we are still waiting for his mentee to call. “There are still a lot of things to figure out,” he shares.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Later I have a video call with John Bosselman, director of instruction at the public charter school Latitude High School, in Oakland, Calif. Bosselman has been speaking to other educators to learn from them and help him make plans for his own school. On our call, he looks concerned, but in control, sitting at his home work station, a bike leaning against the wall. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It has been interesting,” he tells me. “It was like, ‘We are closing tomorrow. Let’s get ready.’” Latitude High is already set up on Headrush, a specialized learning management system built for project-based learning. But his focus these days is on keeping daily rhythm and rituals that allow for students to be in discussion and collaboration with each other, including regular communication protocols. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Education is about four things,” Bosselman explains. “Culture, structure, time and technology. We have culture and structure in place. We now need to leverage technology and use time in a different way.” Staff are splitting class time between live, synchronous online instruction and asynchronous, or time-delayed, work time in smaller groups.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over at Fannie Lou Hamer Freedom High School, a New York public school named after the African-American civil rights leader that stresses intellectual development and social involvement, Jeff Palladino sits in his principal’s office for the last time in what promises to be a long while. Thirty minutes into the interview, he is asked to make an announcement, asking all teachers to plan for students to collect their digital devices from the school before it closes. Another five minutes into the interview, a puzzled teacher walks in enquiring whether they should use Google Hangouts or Meet going forward. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Palladino tackles all disruptions calmly. They are already on Google Classroom, he tells me. Teachers have been sent best practice notes, they are all planning to check in with students three times a week and student advisory, the “lifeblood of the school,” will continue by video conference. Yet as my second call with Palladino gets delayed, I understand how the complexity of transporting a social, collaborative learning practice to an online environment goes well beyond managing practicalities. This is a school whose kids successfully lobbied the New York City council to change the name of their local street to Fannie Lou Hamer on the 100th anniversary of her birth. That’s the level of impact the school intends to continue to facilitate for its Bronx community.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Looking after children and staff wellbeing is the priority.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At Millennium School, a private middle school in San Francisco grounded in cognitive and neuro-science research, students engage in daily mindfulness practices. Co-director of operations Newton Martin and the teachers have been focussed on ensuring no child gets left out during the Coronavirus emergency and that they have coping techniques. In their last morning assembly, children explored “COVID-19 rumors,” hygiene measures and their own fears. The day after I and Martin speak is the first meeting of a special online council, focussed on finding an offline/online balance and how to deal with the noise of the news stream. At the end of each week, Millennium sends out surveys to families for their suggestions. Kids now have scheduled isometric movement and, to accommodate for family meals, no synchronous instruction in the afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“This is an existential crisis,” Bosselman shares with me. We discuss the Harvard Business Review’s recent &lt;a href="https://hbr.org/2020/03/that-discomfort-youre-feeling-is-grief" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;article on grief&lt;/a&gt;. “We have to take care of the staff if we want to take care of our students,” he says. His focus right now is on helping Latitude High School’s teachers have grace for themselves. Similarly, he acknowledges kids have different home experiences: some have to look after their siblings and learning gaps may deepen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Online learning benefits more students used to independent work, but it limits learning for all.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For these schools, closures are taking place at the end of the teaching cycle, when children normally work independently on personal projects and prepare their final expositions. These weeks will be nowhere as disruptive for these students as the weeks following spring break. My interviewees are concerned about the impact online mandatory instruction will have on the depth of relationships between students and teachers and how this will affect students’ level of engagement and learning. Kids at the schools are used to stepping into the shoes of designers, engineers and architects in studios or makerspaces; taking part in community visits, internships or international trips; engaging in socratic and mathematical discussions, sports and one-on-one coaching.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fannie Lou Hamer is adapting its mode of learning according to students’ engagement and Millennium School is carrying out virtual expeditions, or field trip-like experiences. But how will students receive this instruction over the long term? How will presenting to teachers and peers online impact students’ confidence and delivery? What does character building look like online? These are just some of the questions schools are still grappling with. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Palladino calls it “a great petri dish of schooling.” At Fannie Lou Hamer “habits of mind are the fuel of everything we do,” he adds, following research from &lt;a href="http://williamsedlacek.info/publications.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;William Sedlacek&lt;/a&gt; at the University of Maryland that suggests non-cognitive variables correlate with academic success. Bosselman built his Latitude High graduation profiles on Camille Farrington’s research at the University of Chicago on adolescent development and non-cognitive competencies like social emotional learning. Evidence is still missing however as to how to facilitate deep, intellectual discussions and socio-emotional development over a screen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Opportunities emerge.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Online learning is showing less lesson disruption than in the classroom. The crisis has renewed a focus on family context and personal wellbeing. As some states cancel standardized tests, more schools may adopt a coaching versus assessment-based teaching approach.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many challenges still exist around digitizing a social experience like teaching and guaranteeing deep and equitable learning for all. However, through trial and error, these schools may set new standards for enriched and relevant out-of-school, lifelong learning. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The important thing is that whatever it is we are doing, it is a teachable moment,” says Hyman. Along with the challenge comes the opportunity to design innovative learning experiences and management systems that will last far longer than our current crisis.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
      <media:thumbnail url="https://edsurge.imgix.net/uploads/post/image/13251/remote-1586199240.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;w=400&amp;h=200&amp;fit=crop"/>
      <media:content url="https://edsurge.imgix.net/uploads/post/image/13251/remote-1586199240.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;w=1600&amp;h=800&amp;fit=crop" medium="image">
        <media:description type="plain">Innovative Schools Find Lessons — and Opportunities — in Remote Learning</media:description>
        <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">MicroOne / Shutterstock</media:credit>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>5 Ways That Digital Portfolios Can Expand Learning Opportunities</title>
      <link>https://www.edsurge.com/news/2020-04-06-5-ways-that-digital-portfolios-can-expand-learning-opportunities</link>
      <comments>https://www.edsurge.com/news/2020-04-06-5-ways-that-digital-portfolios-can-expand-learning-opportunities#comments</comments>
      <dc:creator>Michelle Diaz </dc:creator>
      <category>Education</category>
      <category>Technology</category>
      <category>Remote Instruction</category>
      <category>Student Engagement</category>
      <category>Personalized Learning</category>
      <category>Project-Based Learning</category>
      <category>Digital and Media Literacy</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 07:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">
post-guid-80b0ac4d      </guid>
      <description>As educators sift through numerous edtech tools in search of meaningful ways to connect, engage and share with their students, the following questions ...</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;As educators sift through numerous edtech tools in search of meaningful ways to connect, engage and share with their students, the following questions are helpful to consider:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote class="pullquote"&gt;Students are more likely to stay motivated and engaged when they have a say in how the work will be completed.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can educators remotely share knowledge, create new lessons and deliver assignments to their students consistently, quickly and easily using this tool?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will this tool enable educators to assess their students’ understanding and growth over time?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does this tool increase student engagement, motivation and ownership at home and within the classroom?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Digital portfolios address all of the above concerns and more. They should be foundational to every school’s technical ecosystem—for both remote and in-class learning—and here’s why.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;1. They give students voice and choice&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Students are more likely to stay motivated and engaged when they have a say in how the work will be completed. Digital portfolios give students the freedom to creatively respond to assignments while demonstrating authentic learning—creating and curating multimedia to show their understanding and exhibit competencies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This approach supports the whole student. In a personal way, students are able to connect with their educators. Using audio, video and text, students explain who they are, how they prefer to learn and what means the most to them. Progress is captured over time, giving educators and students a clear understanding of abilities, talents and potential. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“It’s not just a single sheet of, ‘Here’s what I’ve done in the past few years.’ It’s more like, ‘Look at what I’ve done in great detail, and get to know who I am too.’” - Noah Wong, 10th Grade Student, Cast Tech High School, San Antonio, TX&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2&gt;2. They bring learning together in one place&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ability to quickly gather 30 different articles on a single topic, or to learn a new skill in a five-minute YouTube video has given students limitless opportunities to expand their knowledge and experience the world around them. This abundance of information has created the need for a tool to help students sort through, synthesize and make sense of the content they are consuming. Digital portfolios facilitate this process, helping students develop organizational skills, and providing them with a space to bring their learning together in one place.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;"If you are interested in giving your students the opportunity to have the most authentic learning experience possible, it all starts with creating a digital hub for their learning experiences to happen." - Jeffrey Bradbury, Educator, Speaker, Broadcaster, Teacher Cast Educational Network&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;blockquote class="pullquote"&gt;The process of creating and curating projects within a digital portfolio develops essential soft skills for the digital age.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;h2&gt;3. They support project-based learning&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;With project-based learning (PBL) and work-based learning (WBL), an educator outlines clear expectations via a rubric, provides opportunities for checking in and sharing feedback, and encourages students to connect and collaborate to complete the assignment. Digital portfolios are an invaluable tool to support these student-centered pedagogies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;PBL and WBL rely heavily on a student growth mindset, which challenges learners to demonstrate their understanding in ways other than test scores or grades. In this type of setting, students use digital portfolios to show their process, track progress and develop a final product. Work is then easily shared with educators and peers, encouraging reflection and interaction with new ideas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The process of creating and curating projects within a digital portfolio develops essential soft skills for the digital age. Students learn to identify problems, find solutions through trial and error, and embrace a growth mindset. Their portfolio then serves as a powerful tool, showcasing how they have cultivated and nurtured these skills.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Problem-solving, team working and communication are the skills that are currently most in-demand in the workplace.” - &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/0B__OTXR_u3RbYkRQX3dKWjNtalE/view?mkt_tok=eyJpIjoiWVdFeE4yUTJaVEppWkRBNCIsInQiOiJrVEkwZnJJZmVUTldjeEJiV0JXcTFpblh6UThnbjc2TmYzb0k4dUl3emdLZmlcL2s4T0ZjcU5Za3JrQWxwZUt6UENla2NzbHpad3VkQm81TnplQUdXXC8yaWxsZk02M0FKZkN4alZuQlwvbklXdXFqZThcLzFYZGhHMmpNYlJYdjh2VDIifQ==" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;The Economist Intelligence Unit: Skills of the Future&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2&gt;4. They promote individual check-ins&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Video instruction is a powerful tool, but it is only one way to stay connected with students, and often leads to a one-to-many dialogue. Digital portfolios allow for daily, individualized, back-and-forth conversation and collaboration. Even in a remote environment, students and educators can easily see each other’s projects, share day-to-day experiences and exchange ideas. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With their own portfolios, educators can create meaningful learning spaces, allowing students convenient access to assignments and templates, as well as a personal connection with their educator. Students may capture their learning without the constraints of a specific class time. Educators can provide in-line commenting, offering immediate, valuable feedback to students.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h5 class="aside-heading"&gt;5 Digital Portfolio Resources for Remote Learning&lt;/h5&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.bulbapp.com/h/blog/a-students-remote-learning-journey/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;How bulb Digital Portfolios Fit Into A Student’s Remote Learning Journey&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.bulbapp.com/h/blog/7-tips-for-remote-learning/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;7 Pieces of Expert Advice on Using Digital Portfolios During School Closures&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.bulbapp.com/u/all-templates-assignments" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Free Remote Learning Templates (K-12)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.bulbapp.com/u/free-resource-templates~2" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Templates Featuring Free Remote Learning Resources (K-12)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.bulbapp.com/u/quick-easy-getting-started-with-bulb-leadership~1" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Quickstart guide for bulb Digital Portfolios&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.bulbapp.com/u/reflection-filling-your-bucket-daily" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;“&lt;a href="https://www.bulbapp.com/u/reflection-filling-your-bucket-daily" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Filling Your Bucket Daily&lt;/a&gt;” - bulbLibrary template for educators, supporting SEL across grade levels&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I don’t want my students to be restricted to the four walls of the classroom. Digital portfolios give them the creative outlet to showcase their work. It’s also a great way to let students see my work...they see a little bit about me.” - Tara Bordeaux, Educator, Lanier Early College High School, TX&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2&gt;5. They provide an alternative form of assessment&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Digital portfolios showcase academic proficiencies beyond test scores. Year over year, students naturally build a collection of their best work—comprising soft skills, talents, passions, reflections and processes. Students are not confined to traditional curriculum and subject matter but instead use portfolios to broadcast their passions and interests or offer context for extracurricular activities. These details provide educators and admission boards a comprehensive view of the whole student.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;blockquote class="pullquote"&gt;A digital portfolio encourages a lifetime of learning.&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Schools who faithfully implement a digital portfolio program see a 33% increase in student completion rates and a 10% increase in GPA.” - &lt;a href="https://img04.en25.com/Web/BulbInc/%7B6ff6eb61-4f95-40ad-848c-f68f0f258027%7D_Skills-for-the-Future_v2.3.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;International Journal of ePortfolio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;A digital portfolio encourages a lifetime of learning. Serving as a record of milestones and capstones across grade levels—a clear summary of personal accomplishments and academic achievements—it is an exhibition of one’s best self, to be shared with anyone of their choosing.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
      <media:thumbnail url="https://edsurge.imgix.net/uploads/post/image/13238/digital_portfolios_remote_learning-1585786578.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;w=400&amp;h=200&amp;fit=crop"/>
      <media:content url="https://edsurge.imgix.net/uploads/post/image/13238/digital_portfolios_remote_learning-1585786578.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;w=1600&amp;h=800&amp;fit=crop" medium="image">
        <media:description type="plain">5 Ways That Digital Portfolios Can Expand Learning Opportunities</media:description>
        <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">Image Credit: Marta Shershen / Shutterstock</media:credit>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Online Learning Book Recommendations: And Why I Read so Few Books on the Topic</title>
      <link>https://www.edsurge.com/news/2020-04-06-online-learning-book-recommendations-and-why-i-read-so-few-books-on-the-topic</link>
      <comments>https://www.edsurge.com/news/2020-04-06-online-learning-book-recommendations-and-why-i-read-so-few-books-on-the-topic#comments</comments>
      <dc:creator>Bonni Stachowiak</dc:creator>
      <category>Education</category>
      <category>Technology</category>
      <category>Coronavirus</category>
      <category>Higher Education</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 05:41:17 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">
post-guid-e183e00a      </guid>
      <description>The following is the latest installment of the Toward Better Teaching advice column. You can pose a question for a future column here.Dear Bonni,In the ...</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;The following is the latest installment of the &lt;a href="https://www.edsurge.com/research/guides/toward-better-teaching-office-hours-with-bonni-stachowiak" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Toward Better Teaching advice column&lt;/a&gt;. You can pose a question for a future column &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSdOUe53YQnq7gzdINDKD6YKDM8AIR3reO6ZTQYYB568FOgT0Q/viewform" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dear Bonni,&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In the midst of this current COVID situation, I'm looking to up my game … as an educator … especially in the online environment. I’m wondering if you might recommend what top three books would you suggest I read outside of ‘Urgency for Teachers,’ ‘Pedagogy of the Oppressed,’ ‘The New Education?’ PS. I’ve ordered your book as well. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;—Tim Carson, Skilled Trades and OER Advocate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;First, allow me to tell you why I don’t typically read books about online learning. Then, after I have really heightened your curiosity and you can barely stand the suspense anymore, I will share a few books that I have found beneficial in growing my skills as an educator. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The way that books have nourished my teaching has been in the area of identifying and refining my teaching philosophy and general pedagogical approaches. I haven’t read many books that are focused strictly on online teaching. Staying more holistic when developing my teaching—whether facilitating learning in person or online—has been central in my reading motivations. Even&lt;a href="https://amzn.to/2JEC1nb" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt; the book that I wrote about productivity&lt;/a&gt; was envisioned initially by the publisher as for online instructors, and then they asked if I would be willing to broaden the audience. Books specifically about online teaching, despite having some appeal to me, generally wind up lower on my ‘to-be-read’ book stack. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Experience Online Learning&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The biggest ways that I have been able to develop my skills in online teaching is to experience it myself. Sometimes that takes the form of becoming a student. For instance, I took an online course taught by Sean Michael Morris through the&lt;a href="https://www.digitalpedagogylab.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt; Digital Pedagogy Lab&lt;/a&gt; a few years back. What I recall about it now is that he didn’t make use of a bunch of different tools. Instead, he used a familiar set of educational technologies, but often used them in unfamiliar ways. He once had us take a photo of where we were as we responded to a discussion board and include it in our answers to some introductory questions. This gave me such a sense of presence and being with the people who were entering into a learning community together. One woman took it a step further and gave her introduction from the seat of her motorcycle, as she traveled around her town. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Technology is not what makes or breaks an online class. Instead, the tech is best when it floats in the background, supporting the overall learning goals of a class without seeming like it is the “show” itself. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Someone who agrees with my perspective on not reading many books about online classes is&lt;a href="https://brocansky.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt; Michelle Pacansky-Brock&lt;/a&gt;. Pacansky-Brock refers to herself as a college teacher turned faculty developer, and she has some good guidance for how to best continue to grow our skills at online teaching: &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I would encourage that people start building their personal learning network (PLN) and follow these hashtags on Twitter: #KeepLearning #HumanizeOL #PivotOnline #OnlineTeaching.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pacansky-Brock stresses how valuable it can also be to take an online professional development course, as I did previously through the Digital Pedagogy Lab. Pacansky-Brock emphasizes that taking an online course is the “…best way to gain empathy for students and an outcome no book can provide.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;An educator who has opened up his course to allow any of us to experience it is Mike Wesch, a professor of cultural anthropology at Kansas State University. Wesch’s &lt;a href="https://anth101.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Anthropology 101 course&lt;/a&gt; is &lt;a href="https://www.edsurge.com/news/2018-08-16-how-an-experimental-online-course-helped-one-anthropology-department-keep-a-professor-and-a-half" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;centered around ten different lessons&lt;/a&gt; that each have a challenge associated with them. Each lesson has a well-curated collection of videos, readings and other resources. After exploring the content, Wesch invites us to click the button to take the challenge. His meaning-making challenge presents three different options for demonstrating and further exploring our learning. We don’t have to be enrolled in his class to access it. In fact, he welcomes us to share what we are learning by using the class hashtag across a variety of social media. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Book Recommendations&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now that I have gotten that part out of the way, here is an actual answer to your question. I’m going to share my book recommendations, along with the specific needs I have found them to best meet in my own teaching.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you want to understand some of the primary educational technologies that have been shaping education for years (and to be better equipped to select tools for use in your classes, I recommend: &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://amzn.to/2UXhQGx" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;25 Years of Ed Tech (Issues in Distance Education), by Martin Weller&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you want to align the teaching and learning goals for your class with a relevant technology and address the why behind its use, I recommend: &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://wvupressonline.com/node/803" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Intentional Tech: Principles to Guide the Use of Educational Technology in College Teaching, by Derek Bruff&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you want to select low-cost, practical tools to support student learning, and be provided with “showcase” examples of the technologies that are shared in the book, I recommend: &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://teachingwithemergingtech.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Best Practices for Teaching with Emerging Technologies, by Michelle Pacansky-Brock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, if you want ideas on how to engage learners and how to structure your course to support students’ learning, I recommend: &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.wiley.com/en-us/Small+Teaching+Online:+Applying+Learning+Science+in+Online+Classes-p-9781119619093" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Small Teaching Online: Applying Learning Science in Online Classes, by Flower Darby and James M. Lang&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since I ended with Small Teaching Online, if you haven’t yet read James M. Lang’s first book in that series:&lt;a href="https://amzn.to/2xQutek" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt; Small Teaching: Everyday Lessons from the Science of Learning&lt;/a&gt;, it is the book that I have picked up more than any other about teaching. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I would be leaving out a significant contributor to my pedagogical development if I didn’t also mention Stephen D. Brookfield’s&lt;a href="https://amzn.to/2JB0Wbn" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt; The Skillful Teacher: On Technique, Trust, and Responsiveness in the Classroom (3e)&lt;/a&gt;. When I read Brookfield’s words, I have this eerie feeling—like he has been in the classroom with me during some of my greatest struggles and can gently nudge me forward into growth—with hope and purpose. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I conclude, I realize that you asked for a list of three books. I cheated and gave you six. Hopefully the recommendations about how these books have shaped my teaching will help you narrow them down a bit. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’m also certain that as soon as I consider this article done, I will think of six more that should have absolutely been included within the list. I appreciate your question and this opportunity to reflect on what has influenced my online teaching practices. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
      <media:thumbnail url="https://edsurge.imgix.net/uploads/post/image/13249/edtech_books_4-1586173231.png?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;w=400&amp;h=200&amp;fit=crop"/>
      <media:content url="https://edsurge.imgix.net/uploads/post/image/13249/edtech_books_4-1586173231.png?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;w=1600&amp;h=800&amp;fit=crop" medium="image">
        <media:description type="plain">Online Learning Book Recommendations: And Why I Read so Few Books on the Topic</media:description>
        <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"></media:credit>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flexibility and Collaboration, Not Waivers, Will Make Remote Learning More Equitable</title>
      <link>https://www.edsurge.com/news/2020-04-04-flexibility-and-collaboration-not-waivers-will-make-remote-learning-more-equitable</link>
      <comments>https://www.edsurge.com/news/2020-04-04-flexibility-and-collaboration-not-waivers-will-make-remote-learning-more-equitable#comments</comments>
      <dc:creator>Alicia Garcia</dc:creator>
      <category>Education</category>
      <category>Technology</category>
      <category>Special Needs</category>
      <category>Coronavirus</category>
      <category>Remote Instruction</category>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 05:35:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">
post-guid-2b6a80a8      </guid>
      <description>As of 2017, about 86 percent of U.S. households with school-aged children have access to the internet. That still leaves millions without, and under ...</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;As of 2017, about 86 percent of U.S. households with school-aged children &lt;a href="https://www.ntia.doc.gov/blog/2018/digital-divide-among-school-age-children-narrows-millions-still-lack-internet-connections" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;have access&lt;/a&gt; to the internet. That still leaves millions without, and under the banner of equity, America is arguing about whether to move schooling online as schools shutter to stem the spread of COVID-19. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A major sticking point is not the access gap, but provisions under three federal laws: the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (IDEA), the Rehabilitation Act of 1973, and the Americans with Disabilities Act (ADA). They were enacted to protect the rights of individuals with disabilities and are designed to ensure that public entities like schools do not discriminate on the basis of disability.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Without a doubt, students with special needs deserve equal access to high quality education. There should be no question that school districts must do everything possible to provide the accommodations required by law to students who need them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But the paralysis incited by concerns over litigation is harmful not only to students with disabilities, but everyone else. Questions about whether school districts are able to provide equitable education to children with disabilities are halting efforts to offer any education at all. The Superintendent of Philadelphia School District, for instance, has &lt;a href="https://time.com/5805932/philadelphia-schools-teach-online-coronavirus/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;stated&lt;/a&gt; that if remote instruction is “not available for all children, we cannot make it available to some.” &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On one side of the debate, some district and federal &lt;a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/education/2020/03/19/coronavirus-online-school-closing-special-education-teacher-distance-learning/2863503001/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;leaders argue&lt;/a&gt; that it is not possible to meet the demands of laws protecting students with disabilities in their entirety, and therefore online education must either be canceled or postponed pending waivers from accountability to these laws. Delivering remote education without appropriate accommodations for the &lt;a href="https://nces.ed.gov/programs/coe/indicator_cgg.asp" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;approximately 14 percent&lt;/a&gt; of students nationwide who require special education could exacerbate inequities and put them at risk of litigation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the other side of the debate, disability rights groups like the Education Civil Rights Alliance &lt;a href="https://edsource.org/2020/proposed-coronavirus-federal-aid-package-could-disrupt-special-education/626718" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;argue&lt;/a&gt; that remote education with appropriate accommodations is possible, and it isn’t necessary to waive any provisions of these laws. School districts, they say, should be accountable for doing everything they can to provide necessary accommodations to students. They suggest that waivers will simply eliminate incentives for school districts to &lt;a href="https://www.huffpost.com/entry/coronavirus-students-with-disabilities_n_5e73fde9c5b6eab779452c40" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;provide education&lt;/a&gt; to students with special needs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A troubling and destructive false dichotomy is fast emerging. There is no reason to believe that education leaders need to throw special education protections out the window in order to offer access to remote education. But it might require flexibility and collaboration between school districts and families with special needs students to map out appropriate plans and make the best of remote learning. To start, for example, both schools and families may need to come to the table for &lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/2020/03/27/821926032/with-schools-closed-kids-with-disabilities-are-more-vulnerable-than-ever" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;virtual conferences&lt;/a&gt; to go over what can be provided to their students during closures—and what can’t. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As this debate rages on, students are missing out on learning. Even as the U.S. Department of Education offers &lt;a href="https://www2.ed.gov/about/offices/list/ocr/frontpage/faq/rr/policyguidance/Supple%20Fact%20Sheet%203.21.20%20FINAL.pdf?utm_content=&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_name=&amp;amp;utm_source=govdelivery&amp;amp;utm_term=" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;guidance&lt;/a&gt; supporting continuity efforts, school districts are wary of proceeding with online and other remote learning options out of concern they will be exposed to litigation. This fear has, for too long, led school leaders to place limits on how it can deliver educational opportunities—rather than expanding them. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Under current federal rules, the state of special education has seen mixed results. Special education students may be getting closer to parity when it comes to access. But they are not learning as well as they could be. According to a &lt;a href="https://www.air.org/sites/default/files/downloads/report/Fulfilling-Promise-IDEA-July-2018.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; by the American Institutes for Research, just 66 percent of students with disabilities graduate high school, compared to 84 percent overall.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Clearly, the system can be better. But that doesn’t mean that civil rights laws need to be broadly waived, or that special education students cannot participate in remote education. There is a path forward.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Adopting an expansive framework that enables districts to approach the provision of online learning through a “test and refine” paradigm—one in which proposed accommodations are evaluated for whether they’re able to help students better access learning content and improved or replaced until they do—doesn’t mean they have to start from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many school districts have already made &lt;a href="https://www.air.org/sites/default/files/downloads/report/ESSA-Digital-Lrng-508.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;considerable progress&lt;/a&gt; in leveraging online learning to improve accessibility for everyday learning activities. Many digital tools, for example, incorporate accomodations like audio reading support that can be helpful to all students. As teachers learn to leverage such tools in their instruction, they can both meet the needs of some special education students and improve learning for others. Those advances can and should be brought to bear on efforts to ensure that online learning is available to every student.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Other examples of successful online interventions come from the special education community itself. Long facing a critical shortage of therapy providers, aids and other in-person supports, the field has benefitted from innovation that has married the emergent technologies of teletherapy and telehealth with distance learning to provide access to high-quality &lt;a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/news/presencelearning-offers-teletherapy-training-online-190400278.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;interventions and services&lt;/a&gt;, even when a person cannot be physically available to provide those services.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not all traditional accommodations may be delivered online. For the families that lack connectivity or devices on which to learn, school districts like Detroit have collaborated with families to provide &lt;a href="https://www.detroitnews.com/story/news/local/detroit-city/2020/03/16/detroit-school-district-learning-packets-coronavirus-shutdown/5063881002/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;learning packets&lt;/a&gt; directly to their doors. In places like Sun Prairie, Wisconsin, schools &lt;a href="https://madison.com/wsj/news/local/education/local_schools/schools-go-digital-several-dane-county-districts-move-to-online/article_a6566549-3885-572e-b99a-77c5447128e9.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;bridge the gap&lt;/a&gt; by conducting regular check-ins by telephone. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;America’s legacy of approaching the provision of special education as a battle to be won does not serve any families well right now, when everyone needs access to high-quality, remote education. But it also doesn’t serve the field in general, and this is an important opportunity to rethink the way that special education is designed and delivered, whether in person or in school. Instead, the focus should turn toward a relentless push for innovation that truly enables all children to access the learning they need to succeed. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The only path forward that aligns the expansive spirit of the law with the unusual demands posed by mass school closures is to offer remote education that incorporates and provides opportunities to build upon the best accommodations available. Education leaders and disability rights advocates must work together on acceptable solutions because every child’s access to education hangs in the balance.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
      <media:thumbnail url="https://edsurge.imgix.net/uploads/post/image/13247/flexibility-1585938170.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;w=400&amp;h=200&amp;fit=crop"/>
      <media:content url="https://edsurge.imgix.net/uploads/post/image/13247/flexibility-1585938170.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;w=1600&amp;h=800&amp;fit=crop" medium="image">
        <media:description type="plain">Flexibility and Collaboration, Not Waivers, Will Make Remote Learning More Equitable</media:description>
        <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">ArtMari / Shutterstock</media:credit>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Will Students Take AP Tests During the Pandemic? At Home, With an Open Book. 
</title>
      <link>https://www.edsurge.com/news/2020-04-03-how-will-students-take-ap-tests-during-the-pandemic-at-home-with-an-open-book</link>
      <comments>https://www.edsurge.com/news/2020-04-03-how-will-students-take-ap-tests-during-the-pandemic-at-home-with-an-open-book#comments</comments>
      <dc:creator>Rebecca Koenig</dc:creator>
      <category>Education</category>
      <category>Technology</category>
      <category>Coronavirus</category>
      <category>Assessments</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 16:41:26 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">
post-guid-e27e323f      </guid>
      <description> Changes to a major standardized test usually take months—or even years—to develop and are typically announced well in advance of the first official ...</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt; Changes to a major standardized test usually take months—or even years—to develop and are typically announced well in advance of the first official exam sitting. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not so during a pandemic. On April 3, the College Board offered details about alterations to the AP tests it will administer this May. The changes were made due to school closures prompted by the spread of COVID-19—which in a growing number of states may last until fall. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Instead of the usual multiple-hour marathon of multiple choice and essay questions, this spring exams in most subjects will last 45 minutes and consist of one or two free-response questions. Students won’t work in neat rows in their school gyms or test centers; rather, test takers will be able to complete their exams at home, using any piece of technology available to them—computer, smartphone or tablet. They can even write their responses by hand and take a photo of the results to submit for scoring. (Students who need help accessing digital tools can contact the College Board with &lt;a href="https://collegeboard.tfaforms.net/74" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;this form&lt;/a&gt;.) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While usual security rules prohibit students from bringing to a testing room much more than a few pencils, this year’s AP exams will be open book and open note. That’s similar to many college-level exams, the College Board said in its announcement about the changes. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The exam format and questions are being designed specifically for an at-home administration, so points will not be earned from content that can be found in textbooks or online,” the nonprofit organization explained. “However, students taking the exams may not consult with any other individuals during the testing period.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Exams will be held from May 11 through May 22. Makeup tests will be available from June 1 through 5. Each subject will be offered at the same day and time worldwide. For example, in Hawaii, exams will start at 6 a.m., while on the East Coast, they’ll start at noon. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Students who prefer not to take the exam this year can cancel at no charge (although the College Board notes that refund policies are determined by individual schools and test centers). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For a student weighing whether to sit for an AP test under these stressful circumstances, one big question might be whether colleges will accept the results of these somewhat improvised exams for credit. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The College Board isn’t making promises. But for now, the nonprofit says, “We're confident that the vast majority of higher ed institutions will award college credit as they have in the past. We've spoken with hundreds of institutions across the country that support our solution for this year's AP Exams.”&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
      <media:thumbnail url="https://edsurge.imgix.net/uploads/post/image/13248/shutterstock_610111481-1585953575.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;w=400&amp;h=200&amp;fit=crop"/>
      <media:content url="https://edsurge.imgix.net/uploads/post/image/13248/shutterstock_610111481-1585953575.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;w=1600&amp;h=800&amp;fit=crop" medium="image">
        <media:description type="plain">How Will Students Take AP Tests During the Pandemic? At Home, With an Open Book. 
</media:description>
        <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">Africa Studio / Shutterstock</media:credit>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Is a Health Crisis. So Why Is Health Education Missing From Schoolwork?</title>
      <link>https://www.edsurge.com/news/2020-04-03-covid-19-is-a-health-crisis-so-why-is-health-education-missing-from-schoolwork</link>
      <comments>https://www.edsurge.com/news/2020-04-03-covid-19-is-a-health-crisis-so-why-is-health-education-missing-from-schoolwork#comments</comments>
      <dc:creator>Rebecca Winthrop</dc:creator>
      <category>Education</category>
      <category>Technology</category>
      <category>Global Education</category>
      <category>Remote Instruction</category>
      <category>Coronavirus</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 10:20:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">
post-guid-56946853      </guid>
      <description>Nearly all the world’s students—a full 90 percent of them—have now been impacted by COVID-19 related school closures. There are 188 countries in the ...</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Nearly all the world’s students—a full &lt;a href="https://en.unesco.org/covid19/educationresponse" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;90 percent of them&lt;/a&gt;—have now been impacted by COVID-19 related school closures. There are &lt;a href="https://en.unesco.org/covid19/educationresponse" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;188 countries&lt;/a&gt; in the world that have closed schools and universities due to the novel coronavirus pandemic as of early April. Almost all countries have instituted nation-wide closures with only a handful, including the United States, implementing localized school closures. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The world has never before seen this scale of education disruption.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In recent decades, major disruptions to education mainly involved natural disasters, armed conflict or epidemics in individual countries or sometimes regions. Even compared to school closures during previous global crises, such as the 1918 Spanish flu pandemic where &lt;a href="https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jama/fullarticle/208354" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;40 U.S. cities closed schools&lt;/a&gt;, and World War II, where 1 million children in the U.K. were forced out of school, the level of education disruption is much greater today, in part because &lt;a href="https://data.worldbank.org/indicator/SE.PRM.NENR" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;90 percent&lt;/a&gt; of the world’s young people are enrolled in primary school now—versus &lt;a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1787/888933095666" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;40 percent&lt;/a&gt; in 1920. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today, there are strong &lt;a href="https://www.brookings.edu/research/covid-19-and-school-closures-what-can-countries-learn-from-past-emergencies/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;practices and approaches&lt;/a&gt; that the humanitarian community employs across almost any case in which education is disrupted for a protracted period of time. And some of the best strategies for sustaining education in emergencies have come from humanitarian crises like Sudan and Liberia. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Having worked on helping sustain education amid crises in over 20 countries, I’ve learned that one of the first things you do, after finding creative ways to continue educational activities, is incorporate life-saving health and safety messages. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the early stages of the Darfur crisis in Sudan, I watched children led by an adult volunteer gather regularly under a tree or jerry-rigged tent to sing songs, play games and learn about how to stay safe in a new environment. Studying math, reading and writing was not the top priority; it was slowly integrated over time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The focus was on providing a normalizing routine for children who had been recently uprooted from their home and communicating urgent public health information and training. To mitigate the very real risk of cholera, everyone in the community had to learn where safe water was, where defecation should occur, and how to correctly wash their hands. Sharing the latest public health guidance through education networks was a powerful way to make sure children and their families knew what they had to do to protect themselves. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yet, this week when I received my third-grade son’s packet to support remote learning while his school is closed, it had no information about COVID-19. Rather, it was a series of math, reading, drama and science assignments—useful for continuing his learning, but clearly a missed opportunity for ensuring that he, and by extension his family, knew exactly what to do to mitigate the spread of COVID-19. Where were the age-appropriate materials that would equip students with the latest advice on how to stay safe? &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Information from organizations such as the World Health Organization, which has several short videos on &lt;a href="https://www.who.int/emergencies/diseases/novel-coronavirus-2019/advice-for-public/videos" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;steps to stay safe&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3PmVJQUCm4E" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;appropriate hand-washing techniques&lt;/a&gt;, or catchy &lt;a href="https://www.cdc.gov/handwashing/posters.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;posters&lt;/a&gt; on the topic from the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, could easily be disseminated through schools. UNICEF has a &lt;a href="https://www.unicef.org/coronavirus/fact-or-fiction-how-much-do-you-actually-know-about-coronavirus-covid-19" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;short quiz&lt;/a&gt; to help students and families differentiate COVID-19 facts from fiction, and there is a range of general guidance for parents in talking to their children about COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, there is a remarkable dearth of easily accessible, age-appropriate materials that teachers can immediately use. Such resources could effectively illustrate exactly what staying six feet away from someone else looks like (the length of the average man laying down), how to effectively sanitize your home, and proper social-distancing etiquette when passing someone on the sidewalk or park.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Schools have long been used as vehicles to spread crucial public health information to not just students, but to their parents as well. This is true not only in humanitarian emergencies. In the U.S., schools have served as an effective channel for promoting behavior change on topics as diverse as &lt;a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4360839/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;smoking cessation&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://letsmove.obamawhitehouse.archives.gov/achievements" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;childhood obesity reduction&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In some ways, this crisis presents an opportunity for leveraging educational activities to message necessary changes to public health behavior. Many countries that have closed schools today are moving to some form of remote learning—whether by printed materials, radio programs, or online learning—with a &lt;a href="https://en.unesco.org/news/half-worlds-student-population-not-attending-school-unesco-launches-global-coalition-accelerate" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;global coalition&lt;/a&gt; forming to help provide guidance and support. Given that many young people are learning from home now, it is likely that public health messages will be more quickly than in normal circumstances to make it from the lesson book to the dinner table.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yet in the U.S., the public health community has failed to systematically partner with schools to disseminate their life-saving messages. The CDC has detailed guidance for schools that includes how to prepare a response plan, what to do when a member of the school community has contracted COVID-19, when and how to close schools, and how to disinfect schools. They even recommend using distance learning strategies to ensure education continuity and remind schools to think about school meals. But it provides no specific guidance on the importance of incorporating public health messages into ongoing teaching and learning. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The public health community should immediately partner with school districts to ensure age-appropriate teaching and learning materials are readily available to all educators, including those whose schools have not yet been closed. The state departments of health should partner closely with the state departments of education to ensure ongoing, up to date and regular public health messaging to students. Organizations such as the Council of Chief State School Officers could work closely with civil society coalitions, such as &lt;a href="https://www.learningkeepsgoing.org/?__hstc=12275691.9e529fb0960a22e513c729321e48b3d2.1584740065554.1584740065554.1584740065554.1&amp;amp;__hssc=12275691.2.1584740065554&amp;amp;__hsfp=460571030" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Learning Keeps Going&lt;/a&gt;, a coalition of nonprofits that provides a COVID-19 helpline to teachers and parents. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What we know from continuing education in humanitarian crises is that this important effort takes coordinated action from public health officials and school administrators, and in no way should the burden of deciding what life-saving messages should be prioritized each week be passed to teachers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Much of what we know about education in emergencies comes from low-income countries where school buildings are no longer functional and communities are displaced. Thankfully for most countries with shuttered schools today this is not the case. If, in the remotest parts of war-ravaged Sudan, critical public health messages can be deployed through education activities, then surely the United States and other countries can quickly mobilize the vast remote learning school networks to do the same for COVID-19.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
      <media:thumbnail url="https://edsurge.imgix.net/uploads/post/image/13246/coronavirus-1585928180.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;w=400&amp;h=200&amp;fit=crop"/>
      <media:content url="https://edsurge.imgix.net/uploads/post/image/13246/coronavirus-1585928180.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;w=1600&amp;h=800&amp;fit=crop" medium="image">
        <media:description type="plain">COVID-19 Is a Health Crisis. So Why Is Health Education Missing From Schoolwork?</media:description>
        <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">eamesBot / Shutterstock</media:credit>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>It’s the Dawning of a New Day in the Job Market. Here’s What That Means for Higher Ed</title>
      <link>https://www.edsurge.com/news/2020-04-03-it-s-the-dawning-of-a-new-day-in-the-job-market-here-s-what-that-means-for-higher-ed</link>
      <comments>https://www.edsurge.com/news/2020-04-03-it-s-the-dawning-of-a-new-day-in-the-job-market-here-s-what-that-means-for-higher-ed#comments</comments>
      <dc:creator>Sean Gallagher</dc:creator>
      <category>Education</category>
      <category>Technology</category>
      <category>Coronavirus</category>
      <category>Higher Education</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 10:01:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">
post-guid-3f725592      </guid>
      <description>As 2020 kicked off, the U.S. job market was the strongest in 50 years, and the economy had seen a record 113-month streak of job creation. Across ...</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;As 2020 kicked off, the U.S. job market was the &lt;a href="https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-economy/u-s-job-growth-robust-before-coronavirus-outbreak-hit-shores-idUSKBN20T1SW" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;strongest in 50 years&lt;/a&gt;, and the economy had seen a record 113-month streak of job creation. Across industries, demand for talent was booming. Then, nearly overnight, our world—and the job market with it—suddenly and wrenchingly changed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The COVID-19 virus brought travel to a halt globally, businesses and schools shut down, and workers who were able to do so began working remotely. As a result of this unprecedented worldwide economic pause, a record-shattering &lt;a href="https://www.dol.gov/ui/data.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;10 million workers filed for unemployment&lt;/a&gt; during the last two weeks of March. This is by far the fastest and largest-scale rise in unemployment since record keeping began, and the services jobs that drive the American economy have been the hardest hit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This morning, the U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics released its monthly employment summary for March—which offers one of the first deeper glimpses into how the COVID-19 pandemic is transforming the job market (&lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/march-jobs-report-unlikely-to-show-full-impact-of-the-coronavirus-crisis-11585490400" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;crucially however&lt;/a&gt;, this data only reflects up to the week of March 12 – as the pandemic and its business and school closures were beginning to accelerate in the U.S.). &lt;a href="https://www.bls.gov/news.release/empsit.nr0.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;The national unemployment rate&lt;/a&gt; jumped to 4.4%, up from 3.5% in February, rising across all groups of workers - with workers with lower levels of educational attainment &lt;a href="https://www.bls.gov/news.release/empsit.t04.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;the most vulnerable to job loss&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As we enter a recession, many experts believe that the unemployment rate will spike well into the double digits—to &lt;a href="https://thehill.com/policy/finance/490327-goldman-sachs-unemployment-to-hit-15-percent-quarterly-gdp-to-fall-34-percent" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;15 percent according to Goldman Sachs&lt;/a&gt;, or as high as &lt;a href="https://www.stlouisfed.org/on-the-economy/2020/march/back-envelope-estimates-next-quarters-unemployment-rate" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;32 percent according to the Federal Reserve Bank of St. Louis&lt;/a&gt;. Whatever the exact figure, we’ve gone quickly from nearly full employment to tens of millions of Americans being out of work in a transformative “100-year flood.” Hopefully, this economic disruption will be as short as possible —but a shift of this magnitude will have both immediate and long-lasting implications for the higher education ecosystem in addition to the world of work itself. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;The Future of Work Arrived Early&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Forecasting “the future of work” has attracted the attention of countless CEOs, academic leaders, policymakers, consultancies and others in recent years. Yet suddenly, we must revisit our fundamental assumptions about the economy of the future. Most future-of-work studies rightfully concern themselves with the potential impact of automation and artificial intelligence on the job market and society.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s important to recognize that this crisis will likely only accelerate the march of automation and the adoption of various labor-replacing technologies, including machine learning and AI. &lt;a href="https://www.brookings.edu/blog/the-avenue/2020/03/24/the-robots-are-ready-as-the-covid-19-recession-spreads/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Data from prior recessions shows that this is a clear historical pattern&lt;/a&gt;: after layoffs occur, firms are more likely to replace human jobs with technology. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;a href="https://www.northeastern.edu/gallup/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;past opinion polls&lt;/a&gt; we’ve conducted at Northeastern University, American workers recognize that lifelong learning is critical to staying prepared for these ongoing technology-related changes in the job market. Upskilling workers to compete in a more technology-driven job market—and developing &lt;a href="https://www.polytechnicscanada.ca/opinions/robot-proof-what-joseph-aouns-latest-book-means-for-higher-education-in-canada/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;human skills&lt;/a&gt; to augment or work alongside smart machines—is now even more of an imperative.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Disrupted College Relations&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The rapid downturn in the job market is already having a major effect on the seasonal cycle of college recruiting and summer internships. Early reports indicate that many blue-chip companies &lt;a href="https://poetsandquants.com/2020/03/27/companies-begin-to-freeze-and-rescind-mba-internship-job-offers/?pq-category=business-school-news" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;have begun to freeze or rescind hiring&lt;/a&gt; offers to graduating students. In addition, &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/the-class-of-2020-was-headed-into-a-hot-job-market-then-coronavirus-hit-11585486800" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;internships&lt;/a&gt; are being canceled. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On top of the obvious impacts for new graduates’ job prospects, it’s interesting to consider that as professional work that hasn’t stopped moves online and remote, this could be a catalytic moment for the growing market of &lt;a href="https://www.edsurge.com/news/2020-01-30-to-better-serve-adult-learners-eliminate-the-barriers-between-work-and-learning" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;online experiential learning opportunities&lt;/a&gt; that allow students to gain work experience and work on real-world projects without being physically embedded at an employer site.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To the extent that they have the financial ability to do so, thoughtful employers will continue to invest in &lt;a href="https://www.northeastern.edu/cfhets/wp-content/uploads/2019/11/Designing-Implementing-Work-Based-Learning.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;work-based learning models as a strategic early talent acquisition channel&lt;/a&gt; rather than consider summer internship programs, for example, to be simply a cost center or philanthropic effort.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Cracks in Employer Funding for Education&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The dramatic downturn in the economy also poses significant risks to employers’ role as funders and purchasers of education. Consistent with past recessions, many companies are being forced to &lt;a href="https://www.wsj.com/articles/companies-hit-hard-by-coronavirus-look-to-cut-401-k-contributions-11585746000?mod=hp_lead_pos4" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;cut or freeze benefits&lt;/a&gt; such as 401(k) contributions. With many businesses trimming expenses and laying off employees, it’s likely that employee education benefits will be at risk as well. What had been an extremely competitive market for attracting and retaining employees led to an arms race in benefits, where large employers’ &lt;a href="https://www.edsurge.com/news/2019-08-22-in-a-changing-career-landscape-employers-and-workers-need-a-new-social-contract-for-retraining" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;high-profile investments&lt;/a&gt; in college and university tuition assistance programs captured attention. Historically,&lt;a href="https://www.shrm.org/hr-today/news/hr-magazine/spring2019/pages/education-benefits-present-learning-opportunity.aspx" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt; the availability of tuition assistance benefits declines in recessions&lt;/a&gt;. Thoughtful employers will see ongoing investments in tuition assistance as a strategic investment. Yet, just as this crisis is prompting reevaluation of our country’s social safety nets (e.g., paid time off and healthcare) it is also time to consider &lt;a href="https://news.northeastern.edu/2019/07/09/are-lifelong-learning-savings-accounts-the-answer-to-bridging-the-skills-gap-in-the-age-of-artificial-intelligence/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;vehicles for workers to save for lifelong learning&lt;/a&gt; that go beyond being coupled to individual employers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Likewise, employer spending on training—which often includes university-provided offerings—&lt;a href="https://www.workforce.com/news/training-is-taking-a-beating-in-recession-studies-find" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;tends to decline in recessions&lt;/a&gt;. The executive education market was &lt;a href="https://www.ft.com/content/6a77610e-76f2-11e9-b0ec-7dff87b9a4a2" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;already facing heightened competition&lt;/a&gt; and digital disruption: these pressures will accelerate in the current environment, with even more interest among employers in shorter-form offerings and online delivery. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Acceleration in Online Learning and “Learning in the Flow of Work”&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Aside from the obvious fact that the COVID-19 pandemic has &lt;a href="https://www.edsurge.com/research/guides/sustaining-higher-education-in-the-coronavirus-crisis" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;suddenly moved most campus-based learning online&lt;/a&gt;, a world defined by more telework and stay-at-home orders is leading to a &lt;a href="https://www.edsurge.com/news/2020-03-25-will-covid-19-lead-to-another-mooc-moment" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;surge in demand for online courses&lt;/a&gt; and interest in online degrees, just as it is driving peak demand for streaming video services and online grocery shopping. MOOC catalog site Class Central &lt;a href="https://www.classcentral.com/report/surging-interest-in-online-education/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;has reported a 900 percent spike in traffic&lt;/a&gt;, and course enrollment &lt;a href="https://www.mercurynews.com/2020/03/30/these-silicon-valley-businesses-are-booming-in-the-coronavirus-era/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;has surged at Coursera&lt;/a&gt;. Higher education enrollment has traditionally been &lt;a href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/3488876?seq=1#metadata_info_tab_contents" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;counter-cyclical&lt;/a&gt;, growing in difficult economic times, with the classic example being the most recent–the boom in college enrollment during the Great Recession of 2007-2009. However, in economic crises, potential students’ decision-making often becomes &lt;a href="https://www.chronicle.com/article/Recession-Has-Changed-Views/47151" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;more value- and ROI-oriented&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today’s environment includes more options than in 2009 and could improve the value proposition of &lt;a href="https://unbound.upcea.edu/innovation/alternative-credentialing/microdegrees/national-survey-suggests-that-employers-will-lead-way-on-digital-badging/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;microcredentials&lt;/a&gt;, in that learners could consume courses and programming in smaller, lower-cost portions–increasingly with the potential to stack this into a degree. And, perhaps employers will be more willing to fund job-related microcredentials that meet training needs but still provide employees with the portability of credentials that they desire.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The sudden shift of even more professional work into an online format will only accelerate the blending of learning with working, and the &lt;a href="https://www.edsurge.com/news/2017-11-06-as-corporate-world-moves-toward-curated-microlearning-higher-ed-must-adapt" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;embrace of online training and corporate microlearning&lt;/a&gt;. As more &lt;a href="https://bfi.uchicago.edu/working-paper/how-many-jobs-can-be-done-at-home/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;jobs move to being done online at home&lt;/a&gt;–both in the short-term and in ways that are much longer-lasting —training and professional development is less likely to place-bound or delivered “at the office” or on a campus. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Employers’ investments in digital HR infrastructure and tools to support a more distributed workforce can also be expected to accelerate investments in &lt;a href="https://www.edsurge.com/news/2019-06-24-talent-analytics-skills-based-hiring-and-the-potential-disruption-of-the-degree" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;talent analytics and the use of AI in hiring&lt;/a&gt;, additionally because hiring leaders will have a much greater volume of potential candidates to screen for jobs, and as more hiring and interviewing shifts online.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;New Job Market Demands Mean Shifts in Programming&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is a time of tremendous uncertainty in the job market, just as in our world, where the first order of business is defeating the virus and moving beyond this painful experience. Even if the downturn in the job market is temporary, the societal and cultural shifts will be historic—which means revisiting our fundamental assumptions about demand for educational programs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Like in the Great Recession, the disruptions and dislocations happening today are certain to create a huge need for new retraining programs and resources, especially in forms that are accelerated. This favors what was already a rising demand for accelerated, job market-aligned programming such as bootcamps, apprenticeships and other types of programs that offer pathways to careers. This will apply across the educational spectrum, but it will be especially crucial for the tens of millions of Americans who have lost lower-income jobs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What jobs employers will be hiring for—and what professional programs learners will be interested in pursuing—will also inevitably be reshaped. Just as September 11th inspired people to pursue careers in security, as first responders, or in the military, one could imagine career interests and new government investments focused on areas such as public health, life science and healthcare. The rapid digitization of some areas of the economy and job market will amplify the existing need for IT talent. And, domains such as supply chain, retail, and hospitality will have many of their job structures transformed. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While impossible to predict, this will be a crucial time to observe, analyze and plan for this new future. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
      <media:thumbnail url="https://edsurge.imgix.net/uploads/post/image/13245/planning_for_uncertainty-1585929593.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;w=400&amp;h=200&amp;fit=crop"/>
      <media:content url="https://edsurge.imgix.net/uploads/post/image/13245/planning_for_uncertainty-1585929593.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;w=1600&amp;h=800&amp;fit=crop" medium="image">
        <media:description type="plain">It’s the Dawning of a New Day in the Job Market. Here’s What That Means for Higher Ed</media:description>
        <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">igorstevanovic / Shutterstock</media:credit>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Will K-12 Schools Look Like Post-Coronavirus?</title>
      <link>https://www.edsurge.com/news/2020-04-03-what-will-k-12-schools-look-like-post-coronavirus</link>
      <comments>https://www.edsurge.com/news/2020-04-03-what-will-k-12-schools-look-like-post-coronavirus#comments</comments>
      <dc:creator>Jeffrey R. Young</dc:creator>
      <category>Education</category>
      <category>Technology</category>
      <category>Coronavirus</category>
      <category>EdSurge Podcast</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 07:08:16 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">
post-guid-a4c24a3d      </guid>
      <description>What will K-12 schools look like after social distancing is over and people reassess what they want from school systems after the pandemic?For this ...</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;What will K-12 schools look like after social distancing is over and people reassess what they want from school systems after the pandemic?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For this bonus episode of the EdSurge Podcast, we posed that question to Simon Rodberg, a former charter school principal and author of a forthcoming book from ACSD, “What If I’m Wrong? and Other Key Questions for Decisive School Leadership.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rodberg predicts that this period of forced homeschooling will lead parents to demand different things from schools once they reopen. He argues that school leaders should start planning now for how to deal with the fact that students are getting very different quantities of learning while schools are closed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And he talks about what he’s learning as he’s spending time each day educating his 10-year-old, since school is closed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Listen to the episode of the EdSurge Podcast on &lt;a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/edsurge-on-air/id972239500#" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Apple Podcasts&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://overcast.fm/itunes972239500/edsurge-podcast" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Overcast&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://open.spotify.com/show/5Omg7s9kRYFgt4jEynpdoL" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Spotify&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.stitcher.com/podcast/edsurge-on-air" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Stitcher&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://playmusic.app.goo.gl/?ibi=com.google.PlayMusic&amp;amp;isi=691797987&amp;amp;ius=googleplaymusic&amp;amp;apn=com.google.android.music&amp;amp;link=https://play.google.com/music/m/I7nkf7dakczcktkcfo7enioewc4?t=EdSurge_On_Air&amp;amp;pcampaignid=MKT-na-all-co-pr-mu-pod-16" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Google Play Music&lt;/a&gt;, or wherever you listen to podcasts, or use the player below. Or read the partial transcript, which has been lightly edited for clarity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EdSurge: How will this period of forced homeschooling and online education change K-12 education?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simon Rodberg:&lt;/strong&gt; So the thing I'm thinking about without school happening is what my son is missing while he's not at school. That's another way of asking the question of what is the purpose of school. Why do we send him to school every day? If we're not sending him to school every day, what's not happening?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;h2&gt;This week’s podcast sponsor is Emporia State University’s online Elementary Education program: designed for career changers interested in becoming elementary teachers. &lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Know anyone who might be a good fit? Let us know&lt;a href="https://www.emporia.edu/teachers-college/units/elementary-education-early-childhood-special-education/graduate-programs/ms-elementary/ms-elem-ed-program-of-study/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt; here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;p&gt;I mean he's learning math right now. He's getting it through Khan Academy, through some online work and through meeting with a tutor once a week. He's getting reading. In fact, I think he's probably reading more than he was reading at school. He and his grandma have a standing FaceTime date to talk about writing, and he's sending her some writing that he's doing. So the academic things are happening even more I think then when he was at school. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He's certainly missing socialization and I think that's a big purpose of school is to learn to get along with people and work with people who are not part of your family.I think we'll need to do that [over remote learning, too].&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Social distancing will one day end, and we will once again have to live in a society and interact with people who are not our family. But the big thing that is missing really is not for him, it's for us. We are missing somebody else taking care of our children and we're missing the fact that we can go about our lives for six to nine hours a day without having to take care of them. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think the custodial aspect of school is one of the purposes that schools serve best, which is that they take children and keep them safe and keep them secure and feed them, and whether a school is quote “good” or quote “bad,” whether the test scores are high or the test scores are low, pretty much at every school in the country parents can send their child and be secure that at the end of the day they will get their child back. And I think probably every parent in America, that's what they're missing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It doesn't sound like you're predicting a big uptake in homeschooling after all this.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Parents are going to want to have a place to send their kids again and to have somebody else take care of them in a mass way, where we don't need the one-to-one parent to child ratio all day every day. But what happens there, how lockstep it is, how static it is, I think that will be really questioned, and I honestly think it will have to be. My son is very fortunate that he has two college-educated parents with good internet access at home who are giving him a lot of attention and a lot of resources. There are kids in his class whose families don't have those resources to give and they're going to come back to school in very different places.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don't want him to have to relearn the math that he was supposed to be learning in March and April. He will have learned that math and some more. But there will be kids who haven't. That has always been true. Even when you have kids in the same class all the time, they're learning different things at different rates. But the need for personalizing the learning experience is going to be so much greater after this because kids across America are getting such different experiences during these months of homeschool.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So as I’m picturing it: The day school was like a starting line, and you have some students just continuing or even accelerating their run through academics, and then some students who are probably stalled out, because of their home environment. And so they're all going to come back together in the school building at some point but be at very different points on the run.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I've heard of the factory model of schooling and that was never accurate. We never had kids all learning the same thing at the same pace. But the factory is closed down and we're going back to the medieval home workshops right now. It is crazy to think that we should just go back to the same assembly line after however many months this ends up being.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But schools go back to the factory because it feels like it's the most economical or sustainable way to mass school. Is there some other way that we could try once things get back to normal?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We go back to the factory model partly because we know it, but also because as you said, it's economical. I mean if the custodial purpose of school is what we really miss, we will get it back by going back to the factory model. My hope is that we will have learned from this experience that other things are possible. I think a lot of them are not being done that well right now. My child and every other child that I've heard of in America is watching Mo Willems do pigeon drawings at 1:00 pm ET, and I don't necessarily think that art class should be that way for every kid across America. But there are pieces of online learning that I think would make personalization and make individual pathways much more possible.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I also think that questioning what the topics are that we learn in school should be one of the things that come out of this—that is parents across America are deciding, “I don't think a particular subject is that important for my child to be learning,” maybe that subject actually isn't that important for every child in America to be learning. And I think it’s about questioning some of the decisions that have been handed down through the generations to us and some of the paths that we've been on, now that we are off those paths.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You’ve been a principal. What would your advice be for school leaders?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Put some of your energy towards teaching kids right now—particularly making sure that they have work that they can access that's useful, and that they are getting individualized contact from adults, that there are people checking in with them who are continuing or building a relationship with them so that they know that they're cared about and to the greatest extent possible that they get some feedback on their work. But I would also be putting a lot of energy toward planning for various scenarios when school restarts and how you're going to deal with the missed learning, with the differences in what kids will have learned. Thinking about those long term things and how can you plan in advance for a very different future than the one you might've expected before coronavirus hit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What about your own experience having your 10-year-old son at home. What has surprised you?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well the thing that has been most amazing is we're having a daily recess of bike rides and we have been able to bike down to the national mall in Washington D.C. and climb all over statues in front of the U.S. Capitol that I'm sure the police would be shoo-ing us off if they were around. We've been able to get to the cherry blossoms because nobody is there. We could not normally go visit the cherry blossoms because it's just completely full of tourists in a normal year and there are no tourists right now. That's been what's most surprising. I think that academically just seeing how much he can read and having him actually listen to me when I give him book advice because I'm taking on the role of teacher as opposed to father. Usually he does not take my reading recommendations at all. That's been really great.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the same time there was one moment when he got very frustrated with his math and he treated me like his father rather than the way I think he usually treats his teachers—that is, he's usually not going to yell at his teachers and storm out of the room and I thought, “Boy, this is a moment when I really wish that homeschooling were not happening.”&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
      <media:thumbnail url="https://edsurge.imgix.net/uploads/post/image/13244/school_bus_into_the_distance-1585919066.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;w=400&amp;h=200&amp;fit=crop"/>
      <media:content url="https://edsurge.imgix.net/uploads/post/image/13244/school_bus_into_the_distance-1585919066.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;w=1600&amp;h=800&amp;fit=crop" medium="image">
        <media:description type="plain">What Will K-12 Schools Look Like Post-Coronavirus?</media:description>
        <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">chara stagram / Shutterstock</media:credit>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Online Education Advocacy Group Launches as Dept. of Ed Proposes Loosening Regulations</title>
      <link>https://www.edsurge.com/news/2020-04-02-online-education-advocacy-group-launches-as-dept-of-ed-proposes-loosening-regulations</link>
      <comments>https://www.edsurge.com/news/2020-04-02-online-education-advocacy-group-launches-as-dept-of-ed-proposes-loosening-regulations#comments</comments>
      <dc:creator>Rebecca Koenig</dc:creator>
      <category>Education</category>
      <category>Technology</category>
      <category>Policy &amp; Government</category>
      <category>Higher Education</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 19:27:35 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">
post-guid-25b814a2      </guid>
      <description> To advocate for and on behalf of effective online teaching and learning practices, four organizations are joining forces to establish the National ...</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt; To advocate for and on behalf of effective online teaching and learning practices, four organizations are joining forces to establish the &lt;a href="https://www.nationalcouncil.online/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;National Council for Online Education&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The partnership linking the Online Learning Consortium, Quality Matters, University Professional and Continuing Education Association and WICHE Cooperative for Educational Technologies has been in the works for about a year, says Deb Adair, executive director of Quality Matters. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The collaborative effort stems in part from each organization’s participation in 2019 in rulemaking negotiations with the U.S. Department of Education about distance learning regulations. One task involved figuring out how to define the “regular and substantive interaction” that must take place between students and instructors in online classes in order for them to qualify for federal financial aid.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On April 1, the same day the council launched, the Department of Education announced &lt;a href="https://www.ed.gov/news/press-releases/coronavirus-public-health-emergency-underscores-need-department-educations-proposed-distance-learning-rules" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;proposed rules&lt;/a&gt; that would make it easier for colleges to offer new models for online programs, and also allow more kinds of higher education providers access to aid money, &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/education/2020/04/01/education-dept-advances-long-standing-plan-loosen-regulation-online-college-learning/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;reports the Washington Post&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new council and the proposed governance changes were in the works well before the coronavirus pandemic pushed colleges to rush to recreate their face-to-face classes in virtual formats, sparking widespread debate about whether &lt;a href="https://www.edsurge.com/news/2020-04-02-what-students-are-doing-is-remote-learning-not-online-learning-there-s-a-difference" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;emergency remote instruction counts as “real” online education&lt;/a&gt;. Yet both developments take on new significance because of COVID-19 and the effects it has had on higher education. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Offering guidance about effective online learning in response to the pandemic has &lt;a href="https://www.nationalcouncil.online/priorities" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;jumped to the top of the new council’s priority list&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Higher education, to do what they’ve been able to do in such a short amount of time, it’s amazing, but it’s still not online education,” Adair argues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a href="https://www.nationalcouncil.online/news/joint-response-regarding-covid-19-and-advice-on-transitioning-face-to-face-courses-online" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;joint statement&lt;/a&gt;, the council’s members advocate that “online learning involves the careful and deliberate development and implementation of courses and programs that are designed to be offered online. High quality online courses and programs should be guided by instructional design and pedagogical practices specifically created for online education.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The council aims to help distinguish “this quick pivot to put your stuff up on Zoom” from what carefully designed distance courses can achieve, Adair says, adding, “The fear is that fundamental misunderstanding of what online learning is and what it takes to do it well is going to work against future online efforts, and it will prejudice how student and parents think about online education, and could prejudice how legislatures and folks with other kinds of oversight positions look at online education.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Countering possible bias against online education is one of the council’s broader goals, too. Nuanced research about the efficacy of online learning isn’t always appreciated inside or outside of higher ed institutions, Adair says, citing the work of the &lt;a href="https://uwm.edu/deta/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;National Research Center for Distance Education and Technological Advancements&lt;/a&gt; at the University of Wisconsin at Milwaukee as an example of such scholarship.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Online [learning] has this perceived close association with for-profit education. And for-profit education in the U.S. hasn’t always had a stellar history or reputation because there have been bad actors,” Adair explains. “There are think tanks and individuals that cannot let go of that association and have looked to online learning in general with a very jaundiced eye.” &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indeed, skeptics of online education cite studies suggesting that it “has failed to reduce costs and improve outcomes for students” and that “the gaps in student success across socioeconomic groups are larger in online than in classroom courses,” according to a &lt;a href="http://mason.gmu.edu/~sprotops/OnlineEd.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;2019 paper written by researchers Spiros Protopsaltis and Sandy Baum&lt;/a&gt;, which argued against the weakened requirements for online courses that the Department of Education proposed this week. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the face of such critiques, Adair says, the National Council for Online Education hopes to represent experienced instructional designers, faculty and the entire online learning community that “would like to have an advocate and an honest broker here in these conversations.”&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
      <media:thumbnail url="https://edsurge.imgix.net/uploads/post/image/13243/shutterstock_153032231-1585877151.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;w=400&amp;h=200&amp;fit=crop"/>
      <media:content url="https://edsurge.imgix.net/uploads/post/image/13243/shutterstock_153032231-1585877151.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;w=1600&amp;h=800&amp;fit=crop" medium="image">
        <media:description type="plain">Online Education Advocacy Group Launches as Dept. of Ed Proposes Loosening Regulations</media:description>
        <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">Robert Adrian Hillman / Shutterstock</media:credit>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The 3 Biggest Remote Teaching Concerns We Need to Solve Now</title>
      <link>https://www.edsurge.com/news/2020-04-02-the-3-biggest-remote-teaching-concerns-we-need-to-solve-now</link>
      <comments>https://www.edsurge.com/news/2020-04-02-the-3-biggest-remote-teaching-concerns-we-need-to-solve-now#comments</comments>
      <dc:creator>Torrey Trust</dc:creator>
      <category>Education</category>
      <category>Technology</category>
      <category>Remote Instruction</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 13:45:08 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">
post-guid-13daccf8      </guid>
      <description>With the rapid spread of COVID-19, educators across the country and around the world have been tasked with shifting to emergency remote teaching—a move ...</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;With the rapid spread of COVID-19, educators across the country and around the world have been tasked with shifting to emergency remote teaching—a move from in-person to remote classes &lt;a href="https://er.educause.edu/articles/2020/3/the-difference-between-emergency-remote-teaching-and-online-learning" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;made necessary by&lt;/a&gt; pressing circumstances. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This quick move to emergency remote teaching has left educators scrambling to figure out how to use digital tools, online resources, and apps to continue their teaching at a distance. Unfortunately, across the board, educators have not been prepared to teach well with technology, let alone teach remotely with technology. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While the authors of the 2017 &lt;a href="https://lincs.ed.gov/professional-development/resource-collections/profile-902" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;National Educational Technology Plan&lt;/a&gt; recommended that, “every new teacher should be prepared to model how to select and use the most appropriate apps and tools to support learning and evaluate these tools against basic privacy and security standards,” this has not come to fruition. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In some teacher preparation programs, pre-service teachers are not provided with any opportunities to engage with technology in meaningful ways. Other programs provide a standalone workshop or course about education technology. Meanwhile, fully infused programs, in which education technology is embedded across the curriculum, are rare (see &lt;a href="https://education.asu.edu/ti-defined" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Arizona State University’s Program-Wide and Program-Deep Technology Integration Curriculum&lt;/a&gt;). Similarly, higher education faculty have limited or no opportunities to learn how to teach with technology, including how to find, evaluate, adapt and use technology to enrich learning. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a result, the majority of educators were completely underprepared to design remote learning experiences with technology when states and districts started closing schools for COVID-19. While one benefit of this shift to emergency remote teaching is that teachers around the world are stepping out of their comfort zones to learn new technologies, the use of digital tools, apps, and resources without thoughtful consideration and evaluation presents a number of concerns for student learning, particularly in regards to privacy and student data, accessibility, and the digital divide. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Privacy and Student Data&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;During these pressing circumstances, many educators are curating and sharing digital tools, strategies, and tips for remote teaching with their networks. Businesses and organizations are providing free access to digital tools and apps for teaching and learning (see THE Journal’s ever-growing list of &lt;a href="https://thejournal.com/articles/2020/03/13/free-resources-ed-tech-companies-step-up-during-coronavirus-outbreak.aspx?s=the_it_260320&amp;amp;oly_enc_id=6323B4729901J1A" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Free Resources for Schools During COVID-19 Outbreak&lt;/a&gt;). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pop-up social media spaces and hashtags, such as &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/remoteteaching" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;#remoteteaching&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/CovidCampus" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;#CovidCampus&lt;/a&gt;, and the &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/Temporaryschoolclosuresupport/?fref=nf" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Educator Temporary School Closure for Online Learning&lt;/a&gt; Facebook group, feature numerous posts and discussions about digital tools, resources, and apps for remote teaching. In fact, there are so many digital tools, apps, and online learning resources being shared, some educators &lt;a href="https://www.edweek.org/ew/articles/2020/03/25/flood-of-online-learning-resources-overwhelms-teachers.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;are feeling overwhelmed&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With this rapid push to remote teaching, educators may be jumping into the use of digital technologies too fast. Educator Eric Butash &lt;a href="https://www.edsurge.com/news/2020-03-27-holding-class-on-zoom-beware-of-these-hacks-hijinks-and-hazards" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;noted that&lt;/a&gt;, “as many parents, teachers and students take to virtual conferencing tools for the first time, they are zooming into a ‘digital Wild West’ fraught with as many risks as rewards.” &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Butash is right in pointing out the risks involved in this quick shift to using digital technologies. Without training in how to evaluate technology for teaching and learning, educators may not be aware that they should be reviewing the privacy policies and terms of service of all digital tools and apps before determining whether to use them in their practice. They may not be aware that their use of these technologies might violate students’ privacy rights and put them in unsafe situations. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With Zoom, for example, students might experience harmful or obscene visuals during “&lt;a href="https://www.edsurge.com/news/2020-03-27-holding-class-on-zoom-beware-of-these-hacks-hijinks-and-hazards" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Zoombombing&lt;/a&gt;”—internet trolling during video conferencing. They might experience cyberbullying through the chat feature, by logging into the Zoom room before the teacher arrives and being harassed by classmates, or by having classmates take photos or screenshots of their face during a Zoom meeting and use it in a harmful way. They might give away information to the teacher or classmates about their living situation when they are asked to show themselves on their webcam. They might also have their location data and IP address tracked without their knowledge. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While &lt;a href="https://zoom.us/docs/en-us/childrens-privacy.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Zoom’s K-12 privacy policy&lt;/a&gt; offers more protection to students who login using their school email accounts than traditional users, this policy also allows the school to sign away the privacy rights of students. That is, Zoom can still collect personally identifiable information, information about a student’s school including its location, information about a student’s device, network, IP address, and internet connection, and information about student’s use of and actions within the Zoom platform.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Zoom does state that it complies with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA), the California Consumer Privacy Act (CCPA), and the Federal Education Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA). However, it puts the onus on the educators to ensure that the use of Zoom is in compliance with these policies. For instance, if educators set up a Zoom meeting that is open to the public (whether they mean to or not), they risk having uninvited visitors joining the meeting and identifying students or Zoombombing. If educators post a screenshot of their students on social media to show off their virtual teaching, that is a serious violation of both FERPA and COPPA. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, when educators record students’ faces, names, and other identifiable information on Zoom, that video or audio recording becomes an educational record. As EdSurge has recently &lt;a href="https://www.edsurge.com/news/2020-03-27-holding-class-on-zoom-beware-of-these-hacks-hijinks-and-hazards" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;noted&lt;/a&gt;: “Any images or recordings that include students’ faces or names make these materials an ‘education record’ according to FERPA, which has strict rules around how photos and videos can be accessed, stored and shared.” &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, using digital tools and apps without doing due diligence to examine the privacy policy, terms of service, and features available, can be harmful to students. As an increasing number of companies offer “free trials” of their products to educators during COVID-19 closures, educators must understand that these “free” versions can come at a cost to students’ privacy and safety. Additionally, the way they use these tools can also impact students’ privacy, safety, and learning experiences. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moving forward, educators need better training and support for evaluating digital tools, online resources, and apps for educational purposes. To assist with this, my students and I co-wrote a freely available, open access book, “&lt;a href="https://edtechbooks.org/digitaltoolsapps/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Teaching with Digital Tools and Apps&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the current circumstances, educators can benefit from conducting a thorough review of new digital tools before using them in their teaching, including working with their school or university IT staff to review the privacy policy and terms of service, reading reviews by other educators on blogs or websites such as Common Sense Media, getting connected with educator online communities to learn from other educators about their experiences with the tools (for example, many educators have developed and shared Zoom etiquette infographics for students to prevent cyberbullying and inappropriate uses of Zoom in social media spaces), and notifying students—or their parents or guardians if they are minors—about the potential risks of using the tools and providing alternative options, as necessary.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Accessibility&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The fast move from print-based to digital materials and from in person learning events to digital learning events can create additional barriers for disabled students. For instance, moving from in person lectures to video-based lectures without providing accurate closed captions can significantly limit learning for students who are deaf or hard of hearing. Simply scanning a worksheet and uploading it online as a PDF document without making it compatible for screen readers (assistive technology tools that transmit information on a computer screen to blind or visually impaired individuals) might make learning impossible for a blind or visually impaired student. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Similarly when documents, slides, forms, interactive online tools, and websites feature images, graphs, and charts that do not have alternative text (describing the image to be read aloud by a screen reader), or text and visuals that can’t be adjusted in size, or visuals that use color to signal important information, students who are blind, who have low visual acuity, or are color blind may not be able to perceive important information relevant to their learning. Ultimately, disabled students, who are already a vulnerable population, are going to struggle even more with the shift to remote learning. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Educators and school leaders have “legal obligations to ensure that all students, including students with disabilities, can access online and virtual learning programs,” according to Kenneth L. Marcus, the Department of Education’s assistant secretary for civil rights. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, most educators are not trained how to create accessible digital materials or evaluate digital tools, resources and apps for accessibility. Additionally, most digital tools and apps are not very accessible. For the past four years, I have asked my students in one of the courses I teach, called Online Tools for Learning &amp;amp; Instruction, to evaluate the accessibility of digital tools for the &lt;a href="https://blogs.umass.edu/onlinetools/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Online Tools for Teaching &amp;amp; Learning website&lt;/a&gt;. Students look for whether tools have accessibility statements or policies (i.e., &lt;a href="https://help.flipgrid.com/hc/en-us/articles/115004848574-Flipgrid-and-Accessibility" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Flipgrid and Accessibility&lt;/a&gt;), whether the tool features a Voluntary Product Accessibility Template, or VPAT, (i.e., &lt;a href="http://www.centerononlinelearning.res.ku.edu/vpat/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Center on Online Learning and Students with Disabilities VPAT review database&lt;/a&gt;), and whether the tool can be used with voiceover narration or voice control. While there are many additional features to explore for accessibility (e.g., alternative keyboard input, text resizing, language complexity), through these initial reviews my students discovered that far too many digital tools are not fully accessible. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, big education technology companies, such as Microsoft, Google and Apple, have put significantly more focus on embedding accessibility into their tools. Google Hangouts Meet, Google Slides, Skype and Apple’s video editing app Clips all feature live closed captioning. Microsoft has developed new tools for accessibility, such as Immersive Reader which allows users to adjust how text is presented (e.g., font size, spacing, picture dictionary, translation) and read aloud. Microsoft and Google both have support pages dedicated to teaching users how to create accessible digital materials, including documents, slides and spreadsheets. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While educators are pressed for time in moving their materials and teaching events online, they must seek out ways to ensure that all students are able to access and engage with the digital materials, resources, and tools they use for teaching. Otherwise, they may risk legal implications for not providing accessible learning experiences. Moving forward, educators need better training and support for designing accessible digital materials and learning opportunities. In the current circumstances, educators should start building their knowledge of, and using, accessible tools like the ones from Google, Apple and Microsoft. Educators should also use the Universal Design for Learning &lt;a href="http://udlguidelines.cast.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;framework&lt;/a&gt; from CAST as a guide for creating inclusive educational experiences for remote learners. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;The Digital Divide&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The shift to emergency remote teaching has &lt;a href="https://laist.com/2020/03/27/los-angeles-schools-distance-learning-coronavirus-pandemic.php" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;illuminated&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-03-26/covid-19-school-closures-reveal-disparity-in-access-to-internet" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;exacerbated&lt;/a&gt; the digital divide, or the gap between students who have access to and use technology in meaningful ways to further their learning and those who do not. The digital divide has been around as long as technology has, but the move to remote teaching has made it even more apparent. Some schools rushed to get laptops and tablets to students in need. Internet providers, like Comcast and Spectrum, started offering free Internet access to low-income families. Educators in COVID-19 related social media spaces discussed ideas, shared resources and exchanged teaching strategies to support all learners at home. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, some schools and districts have banned or restricted educators from doing any teaching because it would exacerbate the digital divide. Yet, as Educator Vikki Katz &lt;a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2020-03-26/covid-19-school-closures-reveal-disparity-in-access-to-internet" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;noted&lt;/a&gt;, “the notion that we cut off virtual learning for everybody because we don’t have it for everybody is the right concern, but the wrong solution.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When schools or districts ban teaching for all students, the students who have parents, guardians, or siblings who can homeschool them (or pay for their tutoring) and access to quality technology and Internet will continue learning. Students whose parents don’t have the time to homeschool them, students without access to devices or reliable internet or students who have to share their devices with family members, will struggle to continue learning. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Banning or restricting teaching or the use of technology for learning can be detrimental to the most vulnerable populations of students. Oftentimes, these bans come from a place of fear (e.g., worrying about getting sued due to lack of equity; concerns about students’ misuse of the tools) or lack of knowledge (e.g., being unsure how to teach with technology when students have a range of access). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yet, technology is an incredibly important tool for educators. As the authors of the National Education Technology Plan noted, “technology can be a powerful tool for transforming learning. It can help affirm and advance relationships between educators and students, reinvent our approaches to learning and collaboration, shrink long-standing equity and accessibility gaps, and adapt learning experiences to meet the needs of all learners.” Rather than ban or restrict technology, educators need to be turning toward technology as one of many tools to support student learning during emergency remote teaching or risk exacerbating the digital divide. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of course, there are still a number of students who have limited or no access to technology or the internet. In these cases, educators need to survey their students (or families) to determine what technology and quality of internet access students have access to and then they need to be creative with their assignments. Using the Universal Design for Learning principles, previously mentioned, is a good place to start. These principles encourage educators to provide students with choices for how they access content (e.g., reading, watching a video, listening to a podcast), how they engage with the content (e.g., choosing topics of interest or related to their homes or communities) and how they showcase their knowledge (e.g., choosing which tools to use to display their understanding). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Educators should aim to provide both low-tech and high-tech learning experiences and allow students to choose which type of learning experience to engage in based on their interest and access to technology. By being creative and designing for inclusivity, educators can help prevent the digital divide from magnifying during pressing times. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, educators need more training and support for teaching with technology. The lack of preparation to teach with technology has resulted in many educators scrambling to shift to emergency remote teaching. It has left students more vulnerable than before and negatively impacted learning for students across the country, especially those who need extra support and high quality learning experiences.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Teacher preparation programs need to do a better job of preparing future teachers to find, critically evaluate, and use technology in enriching and transformative ways. Teacher educators, including coaches, faculty development staff, and professional development specialists, need to ensure that educators are ready to shift to emergency remote teaching should the occasion arise in the future. Additionally, education technology companies need to do a better job of informing educators about their privacy policies and accessibility features and how that might impact student learning. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Keeping the lessons learned from this crisis in mind, educators, leaders, businesses and organizations, can be better prepared to support student learning with technology in the future. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
      <media:thumbnail url="https://edsurge.imgix.net/uploads/post/image/13242/concerns-1585857699.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;w=400&amp;h=200&amp;fit=crop"/>
      <media:content url="https://edsurge.imgix.net/uploads/post/image/13242/concerns-1585857699.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;w=1600&amp;h=800&amp;fit=crop" medium="image">
        <media:description type="plain">The 3 Biggest Remote Teaching Concerns We Need to Solve Now</media:description>
        <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">Visual Generation / Shutterstock</media:credit>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Education Is a ‘Wicked Problem’ for Learning Engineers to Solve </title>
      <link>https://www.edsurge.com/news/2020-04-02-why-education-is-a-wicked-problem-for-learning-engineers-to-solve</link>
      <comments>https://www.edsurge.com/news/2020-04-02-why-education-is-a-wicked-problem-for-learning-engineers-to-solve#comments</comments>
      <dc:creator>Rebecca Koenig</dc:creator>
      <category>Education</category>
      <category>Technology</category>
      <category>Artificial Intelligence</category>
      <category>Learning Research</category>
      <category>Higher Education</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 08:56:12 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">
post-guid-b798a9a6      </guid>
      <description>Ashok Goel has a vision for the future of education. The professor of computer science and cognitive science at Georgia Institute of Technology ...</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Ashok Goel has a vision for the future of education. The professor of computer science and cognitive science at Georgia Institute of Technology believes every student and researcher should have access to artificially intelligent assistants that not only help them study facts and figures, but also collaborate more closely with other humans. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Goel has already helped to build such tools for use in his own classroom and worldwide through collaborations with the Smithsonian Institution. He hopes AI bots—such as his most well-known, a virtual teaching assistant named &lt;a href="https://www.edsurge.com/news/2018-04-13-can-a-family-of-bots-reshape-college-teaching" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Jill Watson&lt;/a&gt;—may help to ease the entrenched tensions that make education such a “&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wicked_problem" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;wicked problem&lt;/a&gt;” to solve. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a recent conversation with EdSurge, Goel discussed how learning engineering researchers are applying artificial intelligence to help make high-quality education accessible, affordable and effective on a grand scale. The professor also acknowledged the many ethical questions raised by such efforts. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The interview has been lightly edited and condensed for clarity. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EdSurge: How would you define “learning engineering?”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ashok Goel:&lt;/strong&gt; Learning engineering certainly is a term in vogue now. We usually have been calling it LST—learning science and technology—but it's the same idea. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's the engineering of learning. And the idea is really quite revolutionary, in a way, in the sense that we have always tried to model how people learn—we already tried to build technologies that can help people learn—but we have never viewed learning, until recently, as something that you could completely engineer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, in a way, the term reminds me of another term that came into vogue about 20 years back called “cognitive engineering.” It was a very similar idea. In cognitive science, we can model human cognition, or we can build AI machines that are cognitive in some sense, but cognitive engineering was a term [for the idea] that we can build human-machine interactions that augment cognition in some way. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Learning engineering has a flavor of that. The goal here is can we really engineer learning in a way that we get the results that we want to get.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What problem is learning engineering trying to address? Is there a worry that learning isn't happening to its full capacity, or not for everybody? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goel: &lt;/strong&gt;Education is a wicked problem. “Wicked problem” is a technical term initially proposed in the context of public policy in the late 1970s. There are some classes of problems that are really wicked, and what makes them wicked is they have multiple goals and these goals are in conflict with each other. If you try to achieve one goal, you end up doing worse for another goal. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So education is a wicked problem because you and I can think of multiple goals which are in conflict with each other. We want education to be accessible. We want it to be affordable by everyone. We want it to be achievable, by which I mean, if I register for a class, I should be able to achieve the goals that I want to achieve. Even if it's accessible and affordable, but I can't achieve it, it's not of much use to me. At the same time, we want learning to be very efficient. I should be able to learn what I need very quickly. And it should be very effective in the sense I can make use of it. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The difficulty is we know how to make it very efficient, very effective. All we have to do is to do it individually—one-to-one tutoring—and we know that works very well. But that breaks the point about accessibility [and] affordability, because we cannot have one teacher for every student for every subject in the world. It's just not going to happen. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So those two sets of goals are in conflict. Accessibility [and] affordability is in conflict with efficiency and effectiveness. That's what makes it wicked. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, the question really becomes, is there some way in which we engineer learning in such a way that we can achieve these multiple goals simultaneously? And no one has quite figured it out yet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some approaches to these problems may be policy-related, like funding or charter schools versus public schools, but it sounds like some of them are related to course design, or are technology-related?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goel: &lt;/strong&gt;There is another tension. What makes education really wicked and then connects with the two points you are making about policy and technology is that, on one side, when learning occurs, it occurs one-to-one. So, there is a teacher, there is a student. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the other side, learning is a fundamentally social process. Most of our learning is from our parents, by observing. Some people believe that we learn everything we need to learn by the age of six, just by observing our parents. You don't go to school to learn how to tie a shoelace. But in some sense, tying my shoelaces and brushing my teeth are perhaps two of the most important skills that I've learned. And my parents taught me when I was a little boy. So, a lot of learning is social. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And the question is, how does technology help with social learning also? And the difficulty is that most of the work on technology does not take into account the social learning aspects. If you look at almost all of the work coming [out] on so-called cognitive tutors, or intelligent tutors, you put a child in front of a machine and you expect your child to learn. And that works in very well-defined domains like arithmetic and algebra. It does not work in more open-ended domains like, let's say, sociology, psychology or philosophy, which inherently require discussion, inherently require give and take and learning from other people's stances and arguments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where does your work fit into solutions to these problems?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goel: &lt;/strong&gt;We have not one but several projects. The one that you probably know the most about is about &lt;a href="https://www.edsurge.com/news/2016-05-09-georgia-tech-s-ai-teaching-assistant-fools-some-humans" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Jill Watson&lt;/a&gt;, because it has become famous. I was teaching this online class, there were hundreds of students taking it, there were thousands of questions. My teaching team and I just didn't have the time to answer those questions. So we built this &lt;a href="https://www.edsurge.com/news/2018-04-13-can-a-family-of-bots-reshape-college-teaching" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;AI agent that could automatically answer some questions&lt;/a&gt;, which was good.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One difficulty that happened is that it took us to about 1,000 person-hours to build the first Jill Watson. That's because we didn't quite know what we were doing. It was a research project. We were just sort of wandering around trying to think about how we can make it all work and whether it will actually work. But no teacher is going to put in 1,000 person-hours of his or her time in order to get a benefit of 200 person-hours that he or she may save by not answering some questions. The ratio just wasn't right. As a research project, it was good. But it's not something I could hand over to you or to some colleague and say, go run it in your class.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now, we are building a new technology that we call Agent Smith. It's another AI technology— and we're very excited about it—that builds [a] Jill Watson for you. And Agent Smith can build a Jill Watson for you in less than 10 person-hours. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But another technology that we are very excited about is a virtual experimentation researcher system. Another thing that happens in online learning is that if you're in a university, like Georgia Tech or any other major university, then you have access to a lot of labs—biology, chemistry, physics—and those labs are really important. But if you're an online student, you don't have access to any lab. Then your education—we're talking about effectiveness of education, effectiveness of learning, quality of learning—we cannot guarantee that quality because you don't have access to labs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So what the virtual experimentation research assistant allows you to do—&lt;a href="https://gvu.gatech.edu/research/projects/virtual-ecological-research-assistant-vera" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;VERA&lt;/a&gt;—is to generate ideas and test them. So, you might say, “Why are starfish dying across the West Coast of the United States?” and you can generate a model. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now, model simulation tools have been around for a very long time; for at least a generation, if not more. The difficulty is [that] to build simulations, you need to know mathematical equations or computer programming. In VERA, there is an AI compiler. If you build a model, it automatically sets up the simulation for you. So you don't have to know any programming or mathematical equations. And then you can look at the results of this simulation. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Is the purpose of building tools to improve online education because that is the most accessible and widespread kind of education, as opposed to requiring students to come to a classroom?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goel:&lt;/strong&gt; So, back to the wicked problem: How do we make education that's both quality education and at the same time accessible and affordable? Brick and mortar places like Georgia Tech are very good because they have quality education. But a Georgia Tech, it is neither accessible nor affordable. And it's not just in the U.S. I'm originally from India. When I think about India, most people in India cannot even dream of affording Georgia Tech. So what do we do? How do we help everyone? &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Online education, to me, is one way of perhaps trying to address the wickedness of this problem. It is accessible and affordable on one side, but the question is that, in online education, quality hasn't always been that high.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;From my perspective, learning engineering is one way of seeing whether we can raise the quality that's comparable to that of residential education, and yet keep it accessible and affordable. I don't think we're there yet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A lot of people have recognized by now the idea that MOOCs—you just put it online, people will come, they will learn—didn't quite work out for various reasons. So keeping that idea of open education but tinkering with it, adding these tools in different ways to make it more high quality, makes sense to me.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goel:&lt;/strong&gt; When we go to a physical classroom, students hang out with each other, they form study groups, they work with each other, talk to each other, share notes, they ask each other questions. If someone doesn't understand my class today, they can turn to someone else and say, “I don't know what he was talking about today, can you help me?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So one question for online education is, can we build a new set of tools—and I think that's where AI is going to go, that learning engineering is going to go—where AI is not helping individual humans as much as AI is helping human-human interaction. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you think of Facebook … I work with Facebook one-on-one, Facebook is in front of me and on the screen, I'm working on it. But truly, I use it to connect with other people. I don't care about Facebook, but I care about my family and friends and contacts. That's what I'm interested in.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So we have now built two technical social agents. As students introduce themselves, the Jill Watson social agent is trying to find connections and say, “Hey, you like to play chess, and you like to play chess,” and it’s trying to build a buddy system.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This also raises all kinds of ethical issues. Issues of student privacy. Do I have the right of looking at your introduction and someone else's introduction and connecting you? That might work out, that might not work out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What are the ethical components of all this?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goel:&lt;/strong&gt; Huge ethical issues and something that learning engineering has not yet started focusing on in a serious manner. We are still in a phase of, “Look ma, no hands, I can ride a bike without hands.” We're just so fascinated by our own small things that we haven't started thinking about the possibility that we're going to fall and hurt ourselves or hurt someone else.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There's also the issue of security. We are collecting all of this student data. How do we guarantee its security over long periods of time—not just this semester, but from five years from now or 10 years from now? Students, sometimes, say or do things which are not the smartest things. They wish they [could take] it back. They wouldn't say those things if they knew some machine was watching them. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A whole bunch of problems. Are we entering into the sort of the Big Brotherhood of learning?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There's not only a question of mistrust or distrust, there's also a question of over-trust. The one thing we observed is that a student uses Jill Watson in one class, and one year later, the same student takes another class and Jill Watson is now in that class also, because now Jill Watson by now it is running in about 17 classes, no longer my class alone. And in the meantime, in one year, Jill Watson has improved because we are constantly improving. So the same student looks at Jill Watson today and looks at Jill Watson next year and sees it doing better. And students have started saying, “Wow, this is going on this upward trajectory. Soon, this is going to be like human teaching.” When in fact, I know we are nowhere close to that. But because I see this positive trajectory, it's almost like Jill Watson can never be wrong, it can never give a wrong answer, which, of course, is untrue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What kind of mental models do humans build of AI agents? You can build an agent and introduce it, but humans will immediately build a mental model of that AI agent. And the mental model is not going to be the one that you, as a designer, has. I can think whatever I think of Jill Watson, but once we introduce it, if human beings are interacting with it, they build a mental model of Jill Watson which is completely different from my mental model. And what we have found is that their expectations of Jill Watson are like sky-high. That Jill Watson can answer any questions: “What is the meaning of life?” We need to manage the expectations of humans so that they ask just the right kind of questions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So you teach the tool how to deal with humans, and then you teach humans how to deal with the tool?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goel: &lt;/strong&gt;It's a very good way of putting it. I'm going to build on this idea because learning engineering has not yet started exploring it. We are thinking right now of only one side of the coin, of the two-sided coin that we just talked about. We are thinking about how we can use machines to help humans. We have not yet started thinking about how will humans react to those machines? And what do we need to teach humans about those machines so that the human-machine collaboration is an effective one?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now, that is a challenge, but it's also an opportunity. Most people are scared of AI because they don't understand it. But by introducing AI in various environments, and helping humans understand AI, we can also help humans learn about AI so that they become comfortable with it. But that means we have to explicitly consider that as another research problem. How do we help humans learn about AI so that it can work?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, I think there is another problem with a lot of AI work in learning engineering. Everyone is focusing on architectures and algorithms and data. And that's important. But what people have not necessarily focused equally well—or deeply—is on interactions AI and humans will have with each other. And that's where the kind of questions you're raising come in.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who needs to come into the learning engineering conversations to make sure this happens? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goel:&lt;/strong&gt; That's a great question. One methodology of research is called participation design research, in which you take all these stakeholders and bring them to the table, and they're building tools together. For example, if it's a middle school classroom, [design it] with middle school teachers, middle school administrators, parents, students, not just AI researchers thinking about what will be cool in building AI, which is the way it has been happening so far. So, we have started doing a little bit more of it, but we are still not where we should be. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This has to be participatory, otherwise, we're going to zigzag and not really solve the wicked problem.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Technology always has politics, in the sense that there are power relationships in society, including the classroom. And technology can either disrupt that politics, or it can reinforce the politics. So how do we build technology with the right politics? Not that I have an answer to what the right politics is, but that over time tends to respect inclusion and diversity and equality and equitability and values like that. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don't think in learning engineering [that] we have yet tried very hard to either enunciate what those values are or to think about how do we operationalize those values into the technology that we are building.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Technology should not be left to technologists. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
      <media:thumbnail url="https://edsurge.imgix.net/uploads/post/image/13241/Screen_Shot_2020-1585839180.png?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;w=400&amp;h=200&amp;fit=crop"/>
      <media:content url="https://edsurge.imgix.net/uploads/post/image/13241/Screen_Shot_2020-1585839180.png?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;w=1600&amp;h=800&amp;fit=crop" medium="image">
        <media:description type="plain">Why Education Is a ‘Wicked Problem’ for Learning Engineers to Solve </media:description>
        <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">Gift of Hugh Cassel / Cooper Hewitt, Smithsonian Design Museum</media:credit>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Students Are Doing Is Remote Learning, Not Online Learning. There’s a Difference.</title>
      <link>https://www.edsurge.com/news/2020-04-02-what-students-are-doing-is-remote-learning-not-online-learning-there-s-a-difference</link>
      <comments>https://www.edsurge.com/news/2020-04-02-what-students-are-doing-is-remote-learning-not-online-learning-there-s-a-difference#comments</comments>
      <dc:creator>Ryan Craig</dc:creator>
      <category>Education</category>
      <category>Technology</category>
      <category>Remote Instruction</category>
      <category>Video Instruction</category>
      <category>Coronavirus</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 08:10:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">
post-guid-97ee1974      </guid>
      <description>Having worked at the intersection of education and technology for over 20 years, I never would have predicted that the first excitement at home over ...</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Having worked at the intersection of education and technology for over 20 years, I never would have predicted that the first excitement at home over learning online would be the result of a teacher yelling at my 5th grader to stop using Zoom’s virtual background function to turn his shirt into a forest fire. But I never would have predicted much of what’s happened over the past month, including that my non-French speaking neighbors would be tossing around French phrases like &lt;em&gt;cordon sanitaire&lt;/em&gt; as though they were Charles Baudelaire holding a baguette, or Andre the Giant with a glass of Bordeaux.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Around the world, the media is touting an &lt;a href="https://news.cgtn.com/news/2020-03-12/China-s-e-learning-revolution-in-the-time-of-coronavirus-ONJLTCqkRG/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;online learning “revolution”&lt;/a&gt; as hundreds of millions of students from kindergarten through grad school now learn virtually, including over 70 million in the U.S. alone. The World Economic Forum sees a silver lining in the dark COVID-19 cloud, citing it as a “&lt;a href="https://www.weforum.org/agenda/2020/03/3-ways-coronavirus-is-reshaping-education-and-what-changes-might-be-here-to-stay/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;catalyst&lt;/a&gt;” that could finally change “centuries-old, lecture-based approaches to teaching, entrenched institutional biases, and outmoded classrooms.” Or as one school superintendent reportedly said, “This was a &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/RbnLake/status/1243321189725945856" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;nice, swift kick in the ass&lt;/a&gt; to get out there and innovate.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There’s no question that virtual classroom discussions can approximate classroom discussions. Around the world, some are even producing the kind of learning moments, with focus and insights, that you’d see in sizzle reels for super expensive elite schools. As Yaffa Segal of New Rochelle High School told &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/03/26/learning/what-students-are-saying-about-living-through-a-pandemic.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;The New York Times&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;“The conversation was explosive. Differing opinions flew left and right… I relished… the opportunity to argue and challenge their opinions. I didn’t even realize how isolated I was feeling until I was able to talk to them in a creative and intellectual setting once again.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the same time, what millions of students and their families are experiencing is also leading to a great deal of frustration, prompting a now-viral &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=8U6zU4MXmnA&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;rant&lt;/a&gt; from one Israeli mom:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;“Listen, it’s not working, this distance learning thing. Seriously – it’s impossible… The music teacher of my youngest sent over a musical score this morning. What am I going to do with that information? What, have I got some band in the house? I can’t read music! Just one second, let me pull out my clarinet and help my son with his score… I go from one child to the other. Here’s science, here’s math… How am I supposed to know how to transform an improper fraction… If we don’t die of coronavirus, we’ll die of distance learning.”&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;At home, the limits of Zoom class became clear when my 8th grader told me of students who are recording themselves sitting at their desk, and then playing that video as their virtual background for subsequent classes. Then there are all the distractions, like dogs, family members, students &lt;a href="https://www.edsurge.com/news/2020-03-26-scenes-from-college-classes-forced-online-by-covid-19" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;attending class from bed&lt;/a&gt;, and even offensive &lt;a href="https://www.insidehighered.com/news/2020/03/26/zoombombers-disrupt-online-classes-racist-pornographic-content" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;“Zoombombing”&lt;/a&gt; content. &lt;a href="https://www.freep.com/story/news/education/2020/03/20/michigan-department-education-schools-online-learning-coronavirus/2883849001/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Michigan’s Department of Education&lt;/a&gt; acknowledged as much last week when it announced that Zoom time couldn’t count toward required annual instructional hours for K-12 public schools.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What millions of students around the world are experiencing right now on Zoom and other conferencing platforms is not online learning, but rather remote learning. Susan Grajek of Educause, the association of education technologists, distinguishes remote learning from “well-considered, durable online learning.” Remote learning, she said, is a “&lt;a href="https://www.chronicle.com/article/Covid-19-Has-Forced-Higher-Ed/248297" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;quick, ad hoc, low-fidelity mitigation strategy&lt;/a&gt;.” &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nathan Ecelbarger, founder and CEO of &lt;a href="https://www.freedomlearninggroup.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Freedom Learning Group&lt;/a&gt; (FLG), a leading instructional design services firm that primarily employs veterans and military spouses, describes a well-designed online courses as one that:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;prioritizes engagement by utilizing real-world, recent topics and case studies to stir discussion and even emotion, while incorporating interactivity and immediate measurable achievement;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;makes organization and navigation easy, removing unnecessary steps and clicks that don’t contribute anything to learning;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;rethinks assessment by encouraging research and original thinking instead of memorization; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;always answers the “what’s in it for me” question for students by building intentional learning experiences and getting straight to the point.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;These days—and particularly in this new economy—answering the “what’s in it for me” question often means prioritizing a good first (or next) job for college students. Incorporating &lt;a href="https://info.credly.com/higher-ed-and-digital-credentials" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;digital credentials&lt;/a&gt; to make students’ skills visible to employers, and bringing &lt;a href="https://riipen.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;real-work experience&lt;/a&gt; from employers into coursework, can go a long way to improving student outcomes. You won’t find any of this in a Zoom classroom.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While few online courses live up to these exacting standards, all use some modicum of instructional design. But nearly all are asynchronous and sometimes self-paced—primarily for the convenience of students, instructors, and institutions. And it’s as a result of this kludgy, asynchronous form that online courses, as we’ve known them over the past 20 years, invariably attempt to ape the classroom’s holy trinity: the lesson, the discussion and the assignment. Faithfully replicating these elements—the lecture in written or video form, the discussion via a discussion board, and a written assignment—has been highly limiting for online learning, particularly because some of these elements translate poorly to phones where online learning is now often consumed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Asynchronous online courses are also &lt;a href="http://ccrc.tc.columbia.edu/media/k2/attachments/what-we-know-about-online-course-outcomes.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;notorious for low completion rates&lt;/a&gt;. This is primarily because it’s impossible to control student focus and behavior in such an environment. No matter how well designed, at any time during such a course, students have the choice to open a new app or browser or put the phone down. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So while remote learning has a long way to go in terms of incorporating principles of instructional design to improve student outcomes (and preserve parent sanity), online learning can learn from the experience of hundreds of millions of students who are suddenly endeavoring to learn remotely and synchronously. There is no legitimate educational reason why every online course should not include regular—somewhere between daily and weekly—synchronous classes with instructors and students. (2U, the online provider chosen by the crème de la crème of American universities, insists on synchronous sessions at least weekly.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In so doing, instructional designers should be inspired by the explosive conversations and forest fires currently breaking out across thousands of Zoom classrooms, stop worrying about legitimacy, and break free from the strictures that have limited both innovation and effectiveness.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Will combining the best of remote learning and online learning rival a quality classroom experience? Magic 8-Ball says no. But it will be a lot better than virtually all of the learning currently conducted over the internet.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
      <media:thumbnail url="https://edsurge.imgix.net/uploads/post/image/13239/ryan-1585782548.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;w=400&amp;h=200&amp;fit=crop"/>
      <media:content url="https://edsurge.imgix.net/uploads/post/image/13239/ryan-1585782548.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;w=1600&amp;h=800&amp;fit=crop" medium="image">
        <media:description type="plain">What Students Are Doing Is Remote Learning, Not Online Learning. There’s a Difference.</media:description>
        <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"></media:credit>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Ways Parents Can Bring Social-Emotional Learning Home</title>
      <link>https://www.edsurge.com/news/2020-04-02-10-ways-parents-can-bring-social-emotional-learning-home</link>
      <comments>https://www.edsurge.com/news/2020-04-02-10-ways-parents-can-bring-social-emotional-learning-home#comments</comments>
      <dc:creator>Sara Potler LaHayne</dc:creator>
      <category>Education</category>
      <category>Technology</category>
      <category>Coronavirus</category>
      <category>Social-Emotional Learning</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 04:55:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">
post-guid-069324f5      </guid>
      <description>Most educators know that supporting students’ social and emotional wellness is critical to their overall success. We can’t expect students to process ...</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Most educators know that supporting students’ social and emotional wellness is critical to their overall success. We can’t expect students to process information when they’re distracted, hungry, tired or feel unsafe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now that parents and caregivers are overseeing learning at home, we need to ensure that students continue to build and practice social and emotional skills in meaningful ways, especially when distractions and anxieties from current events and in their personal communities are at an all-time high.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Social emotional learning (SEL) strengthens us as individuals and as communities, especially during uncertain times. When we practice and build our skills in self-awareness, self-management, social awareness, relationship building and decision making, we are better equipped to navigate stressors, anxieties, and challenges. We can solve problems and work together to function at a higher level—in the classroom, at work and at home.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Regular practice is key, just as it is for any other skill like reading, math or shooting a basketball. The same ways we exercise our bodies or practice dribbling a ball, we have to practice identifying, expressing and managing our emotions. Empathy is a muscle we have to flex. By consistently doing so, when we encounter stressful situations, we have a toolkit that we can readily draw upon to help us navigate that stressor or de-escalate the conflict.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So how can we practice SEL at home? Here are ten tips that families can follow.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;1. Take care of yourself, even when it feels like the last thing you can do right now.&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In order to cultivate the social and emotional skills of young people, you must take care of your own mental, social and emotional wellness. Young children are sensitive to the stress of their caretakers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We must stay calm and realistic. They sense when we are worried and anxious, and our emotions directly affect the emotions of our children. We must build in time, even if only 10 minutes a day, for our own wellness practices—journaling, going for a walk, meditating, exercising, for example. Much like putting on our own oxygen mask first before putting on a child’s, we must take care of ourselves during this stressful time so that we’re able to show up for others.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;2. Establish routines and intentionality.&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Routines ground us and provide a sense of safety and security. They are especially important for young children and children who have experienced trauma. Right now, amid the uncertainty of COVID-19, all of us are experiencing trauma. Disasters, forced isolation and other situations associated with the virus break students’ usual routines.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Craft a daily routine for you and your children to stick to. Create intentional time and structure for social emotional learning. This would ideally be 5 to 10 minutes of dedicated practice every day. Use an evidence-based curriculum that provides a thoughtful scope and sequence, allowing students to build upon skills over time. At Move This World, we have opened up access to a library of free &lt;a href="https://www.movethisworld.com/supporting-mental-health-covid-19/sel-video-resources-for-home-free-access/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;videos&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.movethisworld.com/category/supporting-mental-health-covid-19/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;activities&lt;/a&gt; to help you integrate this work into your home more easily.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;3. Presence is not the same as being present.&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many parents may be more physically present than they ever have because they are now home. But that does not mean they are truly present due to increased work demands while supporting learning at home. Many of us are also stressed ourselves, making us less emotionally available.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is important to dedicate structured time to connection and not assume that it will happen organically because we are more “present” now than ever before. Be intentional about when you’re connecting with children and when you are working. Set daily times for playing together, reading books or singing songs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;4. Commit acts of service or kindness for others.&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Practicing kindness for others helps us build an appreciation for our own lives and situations, &lt;a href="https://www.rush.edu/health-wellness/discover-health/health-benefits-giving" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;in addition to improve our physical and mental health&lt;/a&gt;. Phone or write people you know who live alone or are on the frontlines to help them feel less isolated. Write a letter outlining the highlights of your day, or draw a picture of a joyful moment you’ve experienced or something you wish for someone else. Demonstrating kindness gives a more powerful message than just talking about it, and helps build gratitude during difficult times.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;5. Engage in creativity together.&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Being creative is an inherently vulnerable process, especially for older students and adults. By flexing our creative muscles, we can crack open pieces of ourselves that may otherwise be closed off, find opportunities to learn new things about ourselves and others, or learn new modalities to communicate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Examples of creativity in action include cooking or baking together, doing puzzles, coloring or art projects, playing board games, or writing a poem or a song together. Moving together is doubly powerful in getting our blood flowing and activating kinesthetic empathy, or the ability to &lt;a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0197455612000214" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;experience empathy through the movement of another human being&lt;/a&gt;. Try taking turns mirroring each other’s movements or just having a dance party where you each create a new move and teach it to one another. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;6. Celebrate what you can.&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The days can seem long and hard to separate when they are often spent stuck inside. Try to find something small (or two or three things if you can!) to celebrate each day. Celebrate health, a new day, the sun shining. Journal three daily highlights or share them with each other. Research has indicated that when we &lt;a href="https://www.rush.edu/health-wellness/discover-health/health-benefits-giving" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;stop to “savor the good stuff,”&lt;/a&gt; we develop resilience to the negative events that may be happening in our lives.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;7. Practice active listening.&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Do not assume that you know exactly what your child is feeling or is afraid of. Ask questions, listen actively and model eye contact, and then explain what you can in response to their questions. Validate that you see and acknowledge their feelings, fears and concerns.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/250150775_Validating_Young_Children's_Feelings_and_Experiences_of_Fear" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Research tells us to be careful in how we respond to fear&lt;/a&gt; and to be mindful not to redirect or diminish the feeling by saying things like, “there’s nothing to be afraid of.” By validating our child’s emotions we help them better accept and understand their feelings, develop self compassion, and empathize with others.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;8. Help your child express and name emotions.&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This helps young people understand what it is that they’re feeling. If children are struggling to identify their feelings, ask them to express it through drawing, a facial expression, or through a movement in their body. Older students can try journal prompts like: “If I were a weather reporter and my feelings were the weather, it would be _____ today.” They may be able to describe a cloudy, gloomy day but not have the emotional vocabulary to specify their feelings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;9. Practice social emotional learning daily.&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Building important habits takes practice, and just as you brush your teeth every day, students and adults need daily opportunities to identify, express and manage their emotions. Our emotions and stressors change hour to hour and day to day, and it’s important that we check in with ourselves and those around us in order to understand what we all need in order to work through those feelings and move through them together.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;10. Transition mindfully.&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;During times of stress and anxiety, it’s easy to get pulled in by negative thoughts and emotions, and it is difficult to remain in the present moment. Transitions are already challenging for young children, so introduce mindful breathing as you transition between learning time, lunch time and play time. This could mean breathing in for a count of 4 and exhaling for a count of 4.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You could also quietly stretch your bodies and follow the leader, de-escalating and bringing down your “emotional temperature” so that we can quiet our bodies and minds and move on to the next thing with more focus. Identifying a color, and asking children to name everything in the room that’s of that color, is another quick exercise that helps us focus and takes us away from a swirling stream of worry and confusion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These are times filled with worry, fear and uncertainty. It is a challenge we didn’t expect, and the obstacles are shifting each and every day. We need social and emotional skills more than ever, and we can lean into this event as a learning opportunity in how we react to stressful, overwhelming circumstances while juggling multiple responsibilities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We will certainly not be perfect each moment of every day. But by opening an honest dialogue about our emotions and incorporating SEL into our days with intentionality, we are helping ourselves and our children now and for the future. &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
      <media:thumbnail url="https://edsurge.imgix.net/uploads/post/image/13240/10-1585786409.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;w=400&amp;h=200&amp;fit=crop"/>
      <media:content url="https://edsurge.imgix.net/uploads/post/image/13240/10-1585786409.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;w=1600&amp;h=800&amp;fit=crop" medium="image">
        <media:description type="plain">10 Ways Parents Can Bring Social-Emotional Learning Home</media:description>
        <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">Yuliya Chsherbakova / Shutterstock</media:credit>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Serve Students With Special Needs From Afar</title>
      <link>https://www.edsurge.com/news/2020-04-01-how-to-serve-students-with-special-needs-from-afar</link>
      <comments>https://www.edsurge.com/news/2020-04-01-how-to-serve-students-with-special-needs-from-afar#comments</comments>
      <dc:creator>Stephen Noonoo</dc:creator>
      <category>Education</category>
      <category>Technology</category>
      <category>Special Needs</category>
      <category>Remote Instruction</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 16:27:08 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">
post-guid-40582e18      </guid>
      <description>About 14 percent of all public school students receive special education services, and for many of them the switch to remote learning has been ...</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;About &lt;a href="https://nces.ed.gov/programs/coe/indicator_cgg.asp" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;14 percent&lt;/a&gt; of all public school students receive special education services, and for many of them the switch to remote learning has been difficult on families and the schools that teach them every day. How are schools adjusting? What resources are they turning to? And what’s most important to focus on?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To that last question, Sean Arnold, a STEM coach and special educator for the New York City Department of Education, has a suggestion. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Find some way, some moment to connect—especially with elementary students, but all your students really—because they’re challenged,” he says. “They see all this craziness going on around them. They don’t know what tomorrow holds. Why are things so strange? They just want to know at the end of the day that there are people to connect with.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Arnold recently joined Luis Perez, a technical assistance specialist for the &lt;a href="http://aem.cast.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;National Center on Accessible Education Materials&lt;/a&gt;, which is affiliated with the nonprofit CAST, on an interactive webinar, &lt;a href="https://events.edsurge.com/webinars/understanding-the-impact-of-coronavirus-on-k-12-education/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Understanding the Impact of Coronavirus on K-12 Education&lt;/a&gt;, hosted by EdSurge and ISTE, our parent organization. It is a recurring weekly series on Fridays 11 a.m. PT / 2 p.m. ET. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Listen to the audio below or check out the full video &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vb9LbB9vVjY&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;on YouTube&lt;/a&gt;. Below is a partial, condensed transcript below, which has been lightly edited for clarity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is Universal Design for Learning?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Luis Perez&lt;/strong&gt;: Universal design for learning begins with the premise that all learners vary, and that the way that we address that variability is by designing a flexible curriculum that has lots of choice. We know that learners vary in how they engage, how they take in information and also how they’re able to show what they know. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So it’s not always a lecture. We’re using a variety of methods to provide access to the content and then also in how they’re able to express their understanding in a variety of ways. It could be a video, it could be a podcast, it could be a presentation. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sean Arnold&lt;/strong&gt;: I’ll say that in my context of being in New York City schools, Universal Design for Learning just looks like good teaching. It really is just providing options for your students, personalizing the learning for them. So instead of just writing an essay, which some of my students can’t do because they don’t have the tactical skills to hold a pencil, or maybe they struggle with language because they have autism or some other cognitive delay, they’re telling digital stories or they’re expressing themselves through simple three-act math movies. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The connection really is on a real-world level. The curb cuts that we know are for people in wheelchairs also help the guy taking his laundry to the laundromat. It also helps the woman with the stroller. Essentially, these are tools and options that are designed for one specific group, like a ramp to a door, but it helps everybody out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teachers are holding live classes and giving independent work these days. Let’s talk about those terms. What is synchronous versus asynchronous learning?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perez&lt;/strong&gt;: We’ll start with synchronous because that’s what we’re actually doing right now. We’re communicating in real time using a platform called Zoom. (And by the way, Zoom has support for captioning as well.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Asynchronous means that it’s offline, so you can access it in your own time. That can be a website, a blog, a discussion board. It can be one of the oldest forms of digital communications we have: email. It can be texting as well.. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is most important to be focusing on right now?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Arnold&lt;/strong&gt;: The one synchronous thing that I think teachers should do in whatever capacity they can in a given day or week is to find some way, some moment to connect, not just with elementary students but all your students really, because they’re challenged. They see all this craziness going on around them. They don’t know what tomorrow holds. Why are things so strange? They just want to know at the end of the day that there are people to connect with. And that’s something we actually have experienced in New York. Yes, this is a worldwide phenomenon that is new to everybody. But here in New York, we had Hurricane Sandy a few years back and schools got closed. Kids were at home, and we had to connect with them there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have educator friends in California who, in the midst of the wildfires, had kids still showing up to school. You got a class of 30 kids and 25 of them don’t have homes, don’t have possessions or anything anymore. And at the end of the day, the only thing that matters is what my friend said to me: that kids need to go home feeling that they were loved, they were cared for, that they had somebody in their corner. And as much as we need to be regularly doing that for each and every one of our students, the teachers need to be taking that time for themselves too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How do you vet resources for special education and make sure that they’re appropriate for your needs?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perez&lt;/strong&gt;: The first thing is to work with some of the tools that your district has already vetted for you. Something to keep in mind is whether there is a privacy policy for each tool. And then of course, accessibility. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I just did a &lt;a href="https://luisperezonline.com/2020/03/21/three-accessibility-tests-you-can-do-during-covid-19/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; recently on this. There are three things that I look at right away and to determine the accessibility of a tool. No. 1 is: Can I select the text? Can I go in and draw a selection around the text like if I’m going to copy and paste it? Because if I can’t do that, then neither can assistive technology. If a learner needs text-to-speech or they’re using a screen reader, if that text is locked in any way, or if that text is presented as an image, then it’s not accessible.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;No. 2 is keyboard accessibility. Generally when I’m looking at a website or any kind of online tool, I will just flip my mouse over, and then just press the tab key a few times. And I should be able to know as I press the tab key where I am in the interface in terms of the links and so on. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;And the final one is if there is some video, I will play the video and randomly take a look at the captions, just to make sure that they have some grammar in them and are identifying the speakers and so on. Then I know that they’re not the automatic captions. Those are just three simple rules. It doesn’t mean that the tool is completely accessible, but it’s just the first check. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Arnold&lt;/strong&gt;: There are particular tool add-ons like Clicker, which helps students who are barely verbal, as well as Immersive Reader, and Microsoft Teams, which has some really great stuff for multilingual learners and those struggling with language. They have visual prompts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But even more than all of that, you can go beyond the text to digital storytelling. It could be something as simple as Adobe Spark or Book Creator Online. That last one is actually a really nice one to create digital books for your students with embedded pictures, symbols—they’re books that automatically read themselves to students if they’re not capable of it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What should paraprofessionals, assistant teachers and other support staff work on these days?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Arnold&lt;/strong&gt;: This has been the big question from so many people in the city. So there are teachers who are like, "Okay, I’m starting to find my way. I never really used computers with my kids before, but I guess I’m kind of figuring it out. We’re in Google Classroom now and I’m sending them things." Cool. But what’s the role of the speech teacher, or the occupational therapist or the paraprofessional? &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;HIPAA, the health privacy law, has relaxed their guidelines somewhat. You can go on &lt;a href="https://www.hhs.gov/hipaa/for-professionals/special-topics/emergency-preparedness/notification-enforcement-discretion-telehealth/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;the Health and Human Services website&lt;/a&gt; and find that these platforms like Zoom and Microsoft Teams and things have been allowed for teletherapy sessions. You don’t have to have the super highest end security platform. You are not breaking HIPAA guidelines when you’re doing this if you need video, live synchronous conferencing, to make your therapy happen. Soundtrap is an online audio recording platform for speech teachers where they can work with students, and have a chat on the side, either vocally or through text while they’re having them record and work on their speech issues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ll say there’ve been success stories where the paraprofessional is far more technologically savvy than the classroom teacher, and so they’re managing the platforms while the teacher is managing content and information that they want to get out to the kids. We’ve had situations where the paraprofessionals are calling families on the phone, especially if they speak the home language of the student. We are seeing a lot more collaboration in the digital space, rather than kids getting pulled out for sessions. And I hope that when we go back to the physical space, a lot of that can continue.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
      <media:thumbnail url="https://edsurge.imgix.net/uploads/post/image/13237/distance-1585785084.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;w=400&amp;h=200&amp;fit=crop"/>
      <media:content url="https://edsurge.imgix.net/uploads/post/image/13237/distance-1585785084.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;w=1600&amp;h=800&amp;fit=crop" medium="image">
        <media:description type="plain">How to Serve Students With Special Needs From Afar</media:description>
        <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">Creativa Images / Shutterstock</media:credit>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What Students Want Colleges to Know About COVID-19 Shutdowns</title>
      <link>https://www.edsurge.com/news/2020-04-01-what-students-want-colleges-to-know-about-covid-19-shutdowns</link>
      <comments>https://www.edsurge.com/news/2020-04-01-what-students-want-colleges-to-know-about-covid-19-shutdowns#comments</comments>
      <dc:creator>Jeffrey R. Young</dc:creator>
      <category>Education</category>
      <category>Technology</category>
      <category>Digital Learning in Higher Ed</category>
      <category>Higher Education</category>
      <category>Coronavirus</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 14:20:05 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">
post-guid-87c66eee      </guid>
      <description>Most of our coverage of the COVID-19 emergency has focused on talking to educators and administrators about how they’re responding and adjusting to ...</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Most of our coverage of the COVID-19 emergency has focused on talking to educators and administrators about how they’re responding and adjusting to life under school and college shutdowns. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But what about the perspective of students?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For our latest installment of the weekly &lt;a href="https://www.edsurge.com/research/guides/edsurge-live-a-town-hall-style-video-forum" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;EdSurge Live&lt;/a&gt; online discussion series that we are running jointly with Bryan Alexander’s &lt;a href="https://bryanalexander.org/the-future-trends-forum/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Future Trends Forum&lt;/a&gt; about COVID-19 response, we invited three students from different types of colleges to share their stories and give advice to college professors and leaders.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As these students describe it, the move to shut down campus has been emotional, and they have suggestions for what kind of teaching works best now that instruction is online.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our guests were:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Audrey Mullen, a student at Boston College and a former intern at EdSurge who has &lt;a href="https://www.edsurge.com/writers/audrey-mullen" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;written op-eds&lt;/a&gt; about how colleges should use edtech.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Luz Elena Anaya Chong, a student at Texas State University and a resident adviser there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adrienne Davis, a student at Milwaukee Area Technical College who writes for the campus newspaper there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;At one point early in the discussion, several participants attempted to disrupt the proceedings by posting slurs in all caps in the chat window, part of a phenomenon called Zoombombing that &lt;a href="https://www.edsurge.com/news/2020-03-27-holding-class-on-zoom-beware-of-these-hacks-hijinks-and-hazards" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;we recently wrote about&lt;/a&gt;. Our moderators did their best to quickly disable public chat and ban the users who were violating our usage policy, but the incident was a reminder to anyone planning public events on Zoom to be aware of this online vandalism trend. We found &lt;a href="https://keepteaching.usc.edu/tools/zoombombing-resources/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;more tips&lt;/a&gt; for those running Zoom sessions here.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Watch the complete forum below:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Or &lt;a href="https://soundcloud.com/user-134345725/how-colleges-should-respond-to-the-coronavirus-part-2" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;listen to the full discussion&lt;/a&gt; on our EdSurge Live podcast feed:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can also read the highlights from the partial transcript below, which has been lightly edited for clarity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jeff Young: Let’s start by introducing the students who are here and let them tell us what their experience of campus shutdowns was like. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Audrey Mullen:&lt;/strong&gt; At Boston College, we have a very early spring break. So [spring break] was the first week of March, and that was back before there was all this pandemonium around coronavirus. So we were able to have our full week spring break. In that time period, I had friends go to Madrid, I had friends go to Europe. We went to Florida, all these different places. Then we came back to BC on Monday, and rumors were flying around about [campus shutting down] because Harvard shut down on that Monday [which is nearby].&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There was a lot of speculation. [Then on Wednesday,] I was in the library at 5:15 p.m. and got an email. We were thinking that we were going to maybe be there, or maybe take a two week hiatus, or the different options that they talked about initially throughout the process. Then we basically got an email that was like, you have to move out by Sunday, and so classes are over. Being in the library, working on a problem set in the middle of that, I immediately closed the computer, walked outside, and all the seniors are crying.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The moment the email was sent, on that Wednesday, was pandemonium walking through senior housing. It was like the antithesis of a tailgate. So everyone's there just crying … and just saying goodbye to everyone. And then by the Sunday that we had to leave. It was a pretty sad day for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elena Chong:&lt;/strong&gt; For us it was very different, because we have a later spring break, so usually it starts for almost every college on the 9th, but for us it started one week later. So, when Harvard shut down, we didn't know what was going to happen. It was just very nerve-wracking because it's like, OK, these universities are closing, but what is our university going to do about it? &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I work as an RA, a resident adviser, for one of the dorms, and I was like, am I keeping my job? What is happening to all these children that are living here in the dorms? I knew for a fact that all these kids that were kicked out of the dorms are homeless, some of them. So what is going to happen to all these kids? So, it was literally two weeks that we didn't know what was going to happen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think it was on Thursday before we went for spring break, our president sent an email, it was just like, hey, we're going to have one extra week of spring break to give our professors one week for them to plan everything out, because they have to transition all the classes online, and that's a very hard task to do. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adrienne Davis:&lt;/strong&gt; So, what's going on at our school, it was a really big domino effect, too. I also work part-time as a library aide at a high school. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When we first heard about the corona here, the first major school that took action was University of Wisconsin at Milwaukee. There was, I think, one person there that tested for it, and so that prompted the entire UW of Milwaukee system to shut down. The first email I got was saying that all of our classes were suspended until our spring break, and we will come back after our spring break. Our spring break isn't until April, and then the day after I got a notice at my job saying that the high school students were going on their spring break effective immediately as well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's been a little tough, because as a media student, we do everything hands-on. We do all our editing hands-on. We're out in the field, we're shooting stuff. We're interviewing people. We're putting together a newspaper, doing all these things, and it's very hard to do that through a computer. So, effective a few days ago, they told us that all of our classes were suspended indefinitely for the rest of the semester. They told us that our graduation was pushed until December, so we wouldn't have our graduation anymore. And that a majority of our main classes are now online now.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of my advanced editing classes has to be pushed back, I believe until the fall, because since it's a more advanced class, there's just no way that they can put together a course that would be effective for us to still learn how to do it out of software, and make sure that we're all aware of what we're doing. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was supposed to start at University of Wisconsin at Milwaukee in January of next year to do the digital arts and culture program. Now I may not be able to do that until maybe spring or the summer. So it has just really been a domino effect.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Audience question]: What advice would you give to your faculty regarding online lectures? And how could faculty better use live ones? &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mullen:&lt;/strong&gt; I would say be accommodating to time zones. I have a friend who is from Hawaii, and so she has a class from 3:00 a.m. to 8:00 a.m. on her Tuesdays and Thursdays. That is not conducive to learning. That is not what you're paying over $50,000 a year for at Boston College. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I would also say that in terms of online lectures, it's being engaging. But it's awkward in a Zoom call when you ask for an answer and nobody's going to respond. Nobody wants to. I've had professors do a lot of cold calls, and normally I don't love cold calls, I really actually don't like them at all, but I'd say in the terms of the Zoom classroom, it's really one of the most effective ways to get participation. That's what I've noticed within my classes, because the classes that they leave it open-ended, nobody responds.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chong:&lt;/strong&gt; From my perspective, I don't think the time zone really matters because most of our students are from Texas. But I do think that the flipped classroom would really work for a lot of people. I have experienced it before, and I really like it, how they [send a video of a] lecture before class, and they just bring your questions right into [live] class. So, I would encourage professors to do more of a flipped classroom, where they send the material, and then do the Zoom meeting for questions and [discussion].&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I experienced today being put in a break-out room [in Zoom] when I was in a tutoring session, and I feel like that space was more approachable because it's less people, and then you feel less put on the spot. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Audience question]: I know that some institutes these days are starting to come to grips with the fact that they need to think about what they're going to do in the fall. I just read from one person that he suspects students won't want to enroll in essentially an online college because they really want that on-campus experience and they want the face-to-face. I just wondered what you guys think about that. If things are still online come September, would you enroll?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mullen:&lt;/strong&gt; I know for myself, in the fall I'm supposed to be studying abroad in Ecuador. So that adds an extra layer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I know that if classes went all online, and abroad is canceled, I would figure out a way to be in Boston [and still enroll]. I know that that is something that a lot of my peers would do as well. We'd all try to live off campus. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chong:&lt;/strong&gt; Yes, I still do plan to go back—because, I mean, it's college. Even though it might be online, because we don't know when this pandemic's going to end, I still need to take my classes. I still want to take advantage of what the college is offering. I'm not sure if I will move back to where my university is, which is San Marcos. I will still take the classes online no matter what.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Audience question] Would you prefer asynchronous experiences over synchronous ones? [Should classes be live or on-demand?]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mullen:&lt;/strong&gt; I like a combination of the two because if it's just [self-service] online, that doesn't really encourage people to go and to do it. But if it is only [a live] class, that is hard. It's hard to fully focus on a Zoom if you can't pause it and you can't record it and you can't look at your neighbor's notes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chong:&lt;/strong&gt; In one of my classes, it is one day you have to go into the Zoom meeting, but on the other days, the teacher will assign us some work, and then we have to do it. … I really like that—that we don't have to meet every single day at a certain time. For some of them, they didn't make attendance mandatory as they used to in previous classes, but they're expecting us to go, because if you attend some Zoom meetings, they're giving you extra credit, or some motivation for you to still participate in class. So I think that's a good idea.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Audience question] How you are dealing with your stress, and if you've been using anything like mindfulness apps, which are helpful for you? What are you seeing offered at your universities to help you de-stress?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chong:&lt;/strong&gt; What really helps me to de-stress is doing some exercise. So, because they changed laws and you cannot really go outside and do exercise, my school provided some workout videos at home. So that has been really helping me out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Because if not, the stress is going to get too much. I keep getting emails from my professor and it's like, this is due, this is due. I'm uploading this. So, I remember one of my friends told me, "Just take a second and breathe a little bit." &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mullen:&lt;/strong&gt; Oh I've been going on a lot of walks. I don't know about you guys. It's been kind of the big activity. That's a big thing of the day: Go on a walk.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
      <media:thumbnail url="https://edsurge.imgix.net/uploads/post/image/13236/EdSurge_Live_student_panel-1585772224.png?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;w=400&amp;h=200&amp;fit=crop"/>
      <media:content url="https://edsurge.imgix.net/uploads/post/image/13236/EdSurge_Live_student_panel-1585772224.png?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;w=1600&amp;h=800&amp;fit=crop" medium="image">
        <media:description type="plain">What Students Want Colleges to Know About COVID-19 Shutdowns</media:description>
        <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu"></media:credit>
      </media:content>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>4 Items on Instructure’s To-Do List After the Sale of the Canvas LMS Provider</title>
      <link>https://www.edsurge.com/news/2020-04-01-4-items-on-instructure-s-to-do-list-after-the-sale-of-the-canvas-lms-provider</link>
      <comments>https://www.edsurge.com/news/2020-04-01-4-items-on-instructure-s-to-do-list-after-the-sale-of-the-canvas-lms-provider#comments</comments>
      <dc:creator>Wade Tyler Millward</dc:creator>
      <category>Education</category>
      <category>Technology</category>
      <category>Digital Learning in Higher Ed</category>
      <category>Higher Education</category>
      <category>Edtech Business</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 04:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">
post-guid-4314b54f      </guid>
      <description>Even without a pandemic, Instructure faced a transformative 2020. The learning management system provider—best known for its Canvas product popular ...</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Even without a pandemic, Instructure faced a transformative 2020. The learning management system provider—best known for its Canvas product popular among colleges—is officially under private equity ownership. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the benefits of this change is a focus on long-term planning over displays of quarterly growth to impress shareholders, says Mitch Benson, the company’s chief product officer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For example, despite increased activity on the platform—concurrent users on the Canvas LMS were up 60 percent from typical use patterns and video submissions are up tenfold from typical use patterns pre-Covid-19—the costs of moving more data and training more educators will keep the company from a short-term windfall, Benson says. That information might have scared stockholders months ago. But it’s OK by Instructure and its new owner, Thoma Bravo.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“To meet the expectation of demands is priority,” Benson says. “I guarantee that will come at an opportunity cost.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So what else is next for the Salt Lake City-based edtech company? Previous &lt;a href="https://www.edsurge.com/news/2019-10-31-as-instructure-revenue-grows-questions-emerge-over-bridge-corporate-learning-system" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;expansion plans had been put on hold&lt;/a&gt; by a disappointing corporate learning product, &lt;a href="https://www.edsurge.com/news/2019-11-18-canvas-lms-provider-instructure-considers-sale" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;activist investor interest&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.edsurge.com/news/2020-02-18-instructure-ceo-resigns-and-board-approves-new-private-equity-deal" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;an acquisition that became messy&lt;/a&gt; at times. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here is what we expect from Instructure in the near future. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Find A New CEO and CFO&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the first order of business for Instructure is to find permanent leadership. The company in the interim is led by Charles Goodman, an operating partner at Thoma Bravo and former CEO of Thoma Bravo portfolio company Frontline Education, which provides administrative tools to more than 12,000 educational institutions. The company is also on the search for a new CFO. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Goodman will only lead the company temporarily. Instructure has enlisted the service of an executive search firm to find candidates. It may also look at candidates within the company. Josh Coates, for example, served as Instructure CEO for about eight years and is its current executive chairman.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One name floated by company watchers is Ray Henderson, the former chief products officer at ANGEL Learning. After ANGEL was acquired by Instructure rival Blackboard, Henderson served as president of learning platforms for Blackboard until 2013. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another possibility is Scott Pulsipher, current president of Western Governors University.&lt;/p&gt;WGU President Scott Pulsipher talks workforce readiness gap in 2017&lt;h2&gt;Decide About Bridge&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also high on the list is for Instructure to figure out what to do with corporate learning LMS Bridge. The company’s &lt;a href="https://www.edsurge.com/news/2020-01-23-instructure-lays-off-about-100-as-it-urges-shareholders-to-support-sale" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;layoffs in January&lt;/a&gt; impacted primarily employees who worked on this product. It seems likely Instructure will try to sell Bridge or spin it off. The company will not end the product. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Education market analyst Trace Urdan of Tyton Partners says corporate learning budgets are likely to contract with an economic downturn, making a corporate LMS tool like Bridge less attractive to buyers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;That said, the scale of a possible recession could send more white-collar workers back to college to strengthen their skills until the economy improves, which could mean Thoma Bravo is in the education business at the right time. Which leads to the next item ...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Buy Something (and Maybe Invest)&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Though former CEO Dan Goldsmith is no longer with Instructure, his comments on the company’s growth path before the acquisition may provide clues to how Instructure can grow with its new owner’s deep pockets. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The company’s interest in developing a data analytics service—once codenamed DIG and now known as Insights, per Benson—hasn’t gone away. Possible uses of the service include measuring impact of new teaching technologies, engaging students at risk of dropping out and predicting how students perform in courses. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Instructure could buy a company that helps with international expansion. Or it could invest in a Canvas product with a smaller price tag and fewer features that would do better in international markets, dominated by rival Moodle, says education analyst Phil Hill.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But of course, like everyone else in edtech, the rush of schools to online learning could change priorities for Instructure. Demand for synchronous video may have the company in search of features and tools to beef up its Canvas Studio product, says Hill. Instructure may seek a way to increase Canvas' share of K-12 school districts, a &lt;a href="https://www.listedtech.com/blog/k12-lms-market-analysis" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;much more competitive arena&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Online program managers and companies with software designed around student success and administrative services are acquisition targets for Instructure, which appears closely matched with rival Blackboard in the LMS space, says Trace Urdan. Thoma Bravo is unlikely to break Instructure down and sell its remains. “They are builders,” Urdan says.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Please Customers&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hill believes that acquisition drama may have cost the company some of its goodwill with customers and it may take time to rebuild trust and confidence in users. Other LMS companies have seen more wins starting last summer, “a strong indicator of the loss of goodwill,” Hill says. “They have to learn how to listen to their customers again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a way, the COVID-19 outbreak is a chance for Instructure to provide quality customer service in educator training and support during a tumultuous time. To that effect, Benson says that the support team has many temporary workers whose shifts can change based on demand. Plus, other departments within Instructure, including engineering, product management and marketing, have volunteered to help with support and training.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In response to academics’ concerns about the use of student data once Instructure went private, the company formed &lt;a href="https://www.edsurge.com/news/2020-01-17-as-instructure-changes-ownership-academics-worry-whether-student-data-will-be-protected" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;an advisory committee on student data privacy&lt;/a&gt; made partially of educators. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Instructure founder Brian Whitmer also cautions against easy comparisons between Instructure and rival Blackboard, which itself was sold to a private equity firm in 2011 after a time as a publicly traded company.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The market perception is different, the industry as a whole is in a different place, and the product focus isn't as bifurcated as Blackboard's was at the time,” Whitmer said in an email. “The big risk for them is that nobody is really there to push them, so it'd be easy to just lean back and tweak their operational efficiency.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While Canvas’ technology stack and user interface are “starting to show signs of age,” Whitmer said, “there are opportunities to really rethink the teacher/learner workflow that could be really exciting.”&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
      <media:thumbnail url="https://edsurge.imgix.net/uploads/post/image/13234/shutterstock_1208073448-1585694666.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;w=400&amp;h=200&amp;fit=crop"/>
      <media:content url="https://edsurge.imgix.net/uploads/post/image/13234/shutterstock_1208073448-1585694666.jpg?auto=compress%2Cformat&amp;w=1600&amp;h=800&amp;fit=crop" medium="image">
        <media:description type="plain">4 Items on Instructure’s To-Do List After the Sale of the Canvas LMS Provider</media:description>
        <media:credit role="author" scheme="urn:ebu">By S and S Imaging / Shutterstock</media:credit>
      </media:content>
    </item>
 
  </channel>
</rss>